你好，請稍等 您的電話，上校
Yes? Just a minute. Your call, Colonel.
謝謝
Thank you.
你好，約克上校嗎？ 請講
Hello. Captain York, please.
你知道，這件事如果計畫周密
You know, if this thing works out,
將會給我們駐守在從巴丹半島 到新加坡的小夥子們極大的鼓舞
it might give our boys all the way from Bataan to Singapore a big lift.
並把那些倭人 趕回他們的小島上去
And it may pull a lot of Japs back to their islands.
一定會的，將軍 我也相信
- It'll work out, General. - I'm sure it will.
喂，約克，我是杜利德
Hello. Hello, York? Doolittle.
約克，我要你準備好 24架B-25轟炸機和志願飛行員
York, I want you to get 24 B-25s with volunteer crews
儘快調遣到埃格林空軍基地
down to Eglin Field as soon as you can.
這項任務會讓他們 遠離國土三個月
The job will take them out of the country for about three months.
告訴他們這是一項秘密任務
Tell them it's a secret mission.
到達那裡之前 他們是不會知道目的地的
They won't know where they're going until they get there.
對，志願飛行員
That's right, volunteers.
告訴他們不准向任何人談起 這是命令
Tell them they're not to talk to anybody. That's an order.
我過幾天就會來 好的
I'll join you in a few days. Right.
02241呼叫埃格林指揮塔
Zero-two-two-four-one to Eglin Tower.
3架B-25請求飛行和降落指示
Three B-25s request traffic and landing instructions.
請講
Go ahead.
41軍，請靠左飛行
Army four-one. The left-hand pattern.
風向，北偏東北
Wind direction north by northeast.
在3號跑道降落
Land on runway number three.
那是個機場吧？
There's the field all right.
嘿，你們見過這麼寬的跑道嗎？
Boy, did you ever see such a wide runway?
它的確很大啊
She's big all right.
你完全可以閉著眼睛著陸
You could almost close your eyes and get in.
我真想知道 我們會從這兒飛往哪裡
And I'd give plenty to know where we go from here.
我也想知道
Yeah, so would I.
嘿，先別降落，我去拿相機
Hey, don't do anything till I get my camera.
景色怎麼樣，克勒文？
How does she look from the nose, Clever?
太棒了，佛羅里達 棕櫚樹、美洲鱷、泳裝美人
Great. Florida, palm trees, alligators, bathing beauties.
柴契爾，看一下腳下的景色怎麼樣
Hey, Thatcher, have a look at some real country.
沒有比令斯漂亮，長官
It's not as pretty as Billings, sir.
這次飛行帶餅乾了嗎，柴契爾？
Did you keep the cookies this trip, Thatcher?
帶了，飛躍山脈時我很難受 但我還是挺過來了
Yes, sir. I had a little trouble coming over the mountains, but I hung on.
- 02241 - 嘿，等會兒
- Zero-two-two-four-one to flight. - Hey, wait a minute.
我們先等會兒，把飛行梯隊編好
We'll go around, make an echelon right
先飛到機場上空 然後再解散梯隊做得漂亮點
once over the field, then break away. Let's make it pretty.
但願好運
Here's for luck.
關閉
Switch is off!
5分25秒，還不賴 我們走了
- 5:25. Not bad time. - Yeah, we moved.
最好去報修一下左邊的引擎 它的聲音有點刺耳
Better write that left engine up. She sounded a little rough.
我幹得不錯吧，勞森？
Boy, I got some swell shots, Lawson.
你的降落真完美 給我一種藝術的視覺享受
You really made a nice break away. Gave me kind of an artistic angle.
總有一天我要幹一次墜毀降落 這樣你就能看上真正的電影了
Some day I'll do a crash landing so you can get a real movie.
柴契爾說佛羅里達比不上比令斯
Thatcher says that Florida can't compare to Billings.
柴契爾是覺得 任何超過300人的地方…
Trouble with Thatcher is he thinks that any place with more than 300 people
便很擁擠了 是根據最近一次人口普查的，長官
- is overcrowded. - Oh, according to the last census, sir,
比令斯有16,300人口
Billings has a population of 16,380.
16,000，不會吧，柴契爾 你一定把郊區算進去了
16,000! Oh, no, Thatcher, you must be thinking of Greater Billings.
他說對了，克勒文 他們把鄉間的奶牛算進去了
No, he's right, Clever. They count the cows up in that country.
- 對不起，長官 - 什麼事？
- Sorry, sir. - Yes.
- 機場禁止照相 - 什麼？
- Cameras aren't allowed on the field. - What?
是的，長官
That's right, sir.
許多秘密工事都在這裡 這是很嚴肅的紀律
A lot of secret work goes on here, and they're very strict about it.
我根本沒看見有什麼秘密工事
Well, I can't see anything secret from here.
那麼我只好向指揮官報告了，長官
Then I'll have to report you to the Commanding Officer, sir.
這是我的職責
Those are my orders.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
瞧，布裡.霍爾斯通還和我們在一起
Hey, look, Brick Holstrom's still with us.
我還在想明天之前 你不會把那個笨蛋叫上的
We were afraid you wouldn't get that turkey in till tomorrow.
為什麼？那傢伙飛得挺好的
Why, that baby flies so pretty
最後200英里我們很平穩
we floated the last 200 miles.
- 你們準備好了嗎？ - 好了，來吧，布裡克
- Are you guys ready? - Yeah. Come on, Brick.
柴契爾，我去去就來 還要告訴你的住處
Oh, Thatcher, I'll be right back and tell you where your quarters are.
好的
Yes, sir.
大衛，有什麼想法？說說看
Come on, Davey, you've got an idea. What's the dope?
- 我們從這兒會到哪兒去？ - 我告訴過你了
- Where do we go from here? - I already told you.
他們只說了我們會離開本土
All they said was that it'd take us out of the country,
我們會離開3個月 而且還有一定的危險
we'd be gone about three months and that it'd be dangerous.
聽著，我從喬蘭德爾那裡 得到了真實內幕
Look, I got the real dope from Joe Randall.
他說我們是要組成巡邏中隊 去保衛巴拿馬運河
He says they're forming patrol squadrons to guard the Canal.
運河巡邏有什麼危險？
What's dangerous about Canal patrol?
那麼，我們擔心什麼呢？
Well, what are we worrying about?
當我們報到時 斯基就會告訴我們內幕了
Ski will give us all the dope when we check in anyhow.
三架飛機到 長官霍爾斯通、勞森和我
Three ships in, sir. Holstrom, Lawson, and myself.
- 好的，你們的飛機還好吧？ - 是的，長官
- Good. Your ships okay? - Yes, sir.
坐吧
Sit down.
我們住哪，斯基？
Where we staying, Ski?
政府在附近租了間旅館
The government's leased a hotel near here.
他們叫軍官俱樂部
They call it the Officers' Club.
帶來的家眷也可以待在那裡
The men whose wives are coming can stay there.
其他軍官的住處在5號兵營
The other officers' quarters are in Barracks 5.
艾米來了嗎？
Is Emmy coming down?
她幾天之後到 斯基，柴契爾住哪？
- She'll be here in a couple of days. - Where'll I put Thatcher, Ski?
招募兵被安排在12號兵營
The enlisted men are assigned to Barracks 12.
好的
Okay.
- 還有其他事嗎？ - 沒了
- Anything else? - Nope?
至少明早之前沒事了
At least, not until tomorrow morning.
那好，我們再會
Well, we'll be seeing you.
喂，斯基 大夥兒都很想知道發生什麼了
Say, Ski, the guys are all crazy to know what's up.
你和我知道的差不多
You know as much about it as I do.
明早我們就會得到更多消息了
We may be given more information in the morning.
快瞧，夥計，誰來了
Well, beat me, daddy! Look who's coming!
好好好 看來我必須去了
Well, well, well, plant me now and dig me later,
如果不是藍道夫.菲爾德的緣故 怎麼樣，哥們？
if it isn't the pride of Randolph Field. How are you, boy?
最近不錯 我們一聽到這個興奮的消息
Great, Shorty. The minute we heard that razzmatazz,
就知道你肯定就在這附近
we knew you must be somewhere around.
- 你也是自願參與這次行動的 - 當然
- You volunteer for this deal, too? - Sure enough.
他們把我安排在明尼阿波利斯 一個我見過最冷的地方
They had me stationed up in Minneapolis. Coldest country I ever did see.
我極力想去任何一個 能讓我重返陽光的地方
I'd have volunteered for anything to get back in the sunshine.
- 你去過哪？ - 哥倫比亞、南卡羅萊納
- Where you been? - Columbia, South Carolina.
- 鮑勃 - 你好，特德
- Bob! - Hello, Ted.
你們認識？
You guys know each other?
我們一起認識的凱利，就這樣
Oh, we just went through Kelly together, that's all.
- 當然，鮑勃是我婚禮的伴郎 - 婚禮
- Sure. Bob was bridesmaid at my wedding. - Wedding?
沒有人再告訴我什麼了
Nobody tells me anything anymore.
你們搞在一起多久了？
How long you been balled up and chained down?
再過五六天就六個月了
Six months, in five more days.
讓我大吃一驚啊 別騙我啊
Well, blow my foot off. Skin me again, boy.
大衛，你在這兒怎麼樣啊？
Hey, Davey, what are you doing down here?
- 布裡克 - 嗨，唐
- Brick! - Hi, Don.
- 我還以為你在打潛水艇呢 - 是啊，打沉過一艘
- I thought you were hunting subs. - Was. Got me one, too.
- 你也參與這項任務 - 當然，我有一批不錯的隊員
- You in on this deal? - Sure. I've got a swell crew
看起來好像會有什麼大任務 不是嗎？
and it looked like it was going to be something, so why not?
- 我們的行動，有什麼想法嗎？ - 哦，只是預感
- Any ideas what we might be up to? - Oh, just a hunch.
是嗎？快說說看
Yeah? Well, give.
南部海域趕走那些蠢蛋
South Seas. Knock ourselves off a few meatballs.
Yeah?
三點
Three.
好傢伙，莊家得兩點
Honest man. Dealer takes two.
- 我剛才想到 - 想到什麼？
- You know, I just got an idea. - About what?
想到我們會去的地方
About where we might be going.
- 行程看起來會… - 不會不會，算了
The way it looks to... No, that's not right. Forget it.
得兩點
Says two.
- 我也有一個猜想 - 什麼？
- You know, I've got an idea too. - Yeah?
我覺得 你肯定是第一個來到這裡…
I've got an idea you're pretty much of a dope
並且知道內情的
to have come in on this deal in the first place.
為什麼？
What kind of a crack is that?
我不知道你結婚了 有一個不錯的女孩
Oh, I don't know. You're married. You've got a swell girl.
如果我是你的話 就絕不會去冒風險
I never would have stuck my neck out if I were in your boots.
滾開 你說兩點
Go away. You say two?
再跟兩點
And up two.
那些人又被刷掉了
Those guys are off again.
起來，起來 你們以為你們是誰啊
Hey, stand up there. Who do you think you are?
你們飛機上配有導航員嗎？
Have you ever carried a navigator in your ship before, Spike?
我也沒有 直到我們參與了這次行動
Neither have I, until I volunteered for this job.
我們就快知道一些奇妙的消息了 我有一種感黨
Oh, we're going to see some fancy stuff, all right. I kind of got a feeling.
拿我們去對付那些臭雞貂
Shoot me for a pole cat.
我看見兩個精力充沛的人 背靠背…
Do I see two red-blooded citizens lying on their backsides
還唱著德克薩斯讚歌
while the Texas anthem is being rendered?
起立 你們
On your feet, men.
感覺怎麼樣？ 最近你來自佛吉尼亞吧？
What are you beefing about, Shorty? You're from Virginia.
是的，聰明鬼
That's right, sharp cat,
但我德州的這個朋友在這 而且經常不守規矩
but my pal here, he's from Texas, and he takes offense easy.
- 你好，喬 - 你好，喬伊絲，我得到一些消息
- Hello, Joe. - Hello, Joyce. I've got some news.
嘿，你們安靜些
Hey, you guys, shut up!
安靜，小夥子們 聽著，吉米.杜利德要來了
Quiet, fellows. Listen. Jimmy Doolittle's down here
他現在是陸軍中校
and he's a Lieutenant Colonel now.
吉米.杜利德是南加州的
Jimmy Doolittle! A southern boy from Southern California.
讓我們為吉米.杜利德唱一曲 “德州之眼”吧
Let's have Eyes of Texas for Lieutenant Colonel Jimmy Doolittle.
立正
Attention!
大家好 杜利德中校
Gentlemen, Lieutenant Colonel Doolittle.
請坐
As you were.
你們是自願到這兒的
You men are here because you've volunteered.
你們被告知 這將會是一次危險的任務
You have been told it's a dangerous mission.
現在我不會再告訴你們更多 但我想再強調危險
I can't tell you any more than that now, but I want to emphasize the danger.
當下最重要的是嚴守秘密
The most important thing at the moment is secrecy.
我不想你們去告訴你們的妻子 這裡有些什麼
I don't want you to even tell your wives what you see down here.
如果你們覺得猜到了 將要去哪兒…
And if you think you've guessed where you're going,
那肯定是錯的 但甚至這猜測都不要談論
you're probably wrong. But don't even talk about your guess.
如果這次任務的一丁點消息 走漏了的話…
If the slightest word about this mission gets around,
你們的生命甚至數以萬計人的生命 都將置於危險之中
you will endanger not only your own lives, but the lives of thousands of other men.
現在，我想問你們一個問題
Now I want to ask you a question.
有人試著談起這些事情嗎？
Has anybody tried to talk to you about this?
很好，如果基地內外的任何人…
Good. If anybody on the field or off the field
試看要問起你們關於…
tries to engage you in conversation
為什麼你們來這裡 不管多麼友善…
as to why you're here, no matter how innocently,
我要你們記住他的名字 然後告訴我
I want you to get his name and give it to me
我會把它交給聯邦調查局
and I'll turn it over to the FBI.
這將是一次你們經歷過的 最艱苦的訓練
This is going to be the toughest training you've ever had.
你們將會在同一艘船上 和同一批人在一起
You will have the same crew all the way through and the same ship.
任何失敗的團隊將會被剔除
And the man or the ship that fails will be dropped.
你們將會駕駛 你們覺得不可能的B-25
You're going to do things with a B-25 you thought were impossible.
如果你們有任何雜念 我建議你們趁早放棄
Now, if any of you have any doubts, I'd like you to drop out right now
我保證你們沒有人會想得更糟
and I promise you that no one will ever think the worse of you.
如果你們的妻兒或其他什麼…
If you have wives or children or any other considerations
讓你們在危機中時刻牽掛著 很正常
that might get on your nerves in a crisis, it's perfectly all right.
事實上，放棄是你們的職責
As a matter of fact, it's your duty to drop out.
很好，我們將進行盡可能多的談話 就這樣吧
Very well. We'll have these talks as often as possible. That's all.
今早開始，我們將進行定向飛行
We're going up this morning for an orientation flight.
有四個輔助機場 一、二、三、四
There are four auxiliary fields. One, two, three, four.
依次全部找到它們
Line them up and locate them all.
我不知道會使用哪一個來進行 我們的機密試驗…
We don't know which we're going to use for our confidential experiments,
所以自己都去熟悉熟悉
so familiarize yourselves with all of them.
先自己去轉轉 等一會兒我們再集台
Look over the countryside, and we'll meet here again
下午三點半，還有問題嗎？
at 3:30 this afternoon. Are there any questions?
長官，我引擎中的塞子正在更換中
Sir, the plugs are being changed in my engines.
為了節省時間 我能搭鐘斯的飛機嗎？
To save time, may I go along in Jones' ship?
可以，史密斯 你們可以去自己的飛機了
Right, Smith. All right. You can go to your ship now.
對我來說，你很長時間都沒去…
It looks to me like it's going to be a long time
比令斯主幹道遊蕩了，柴契爾
before you swing down Main Street of Billings again, Thatcher.
在比令斯，長官 主幹道是明尼蘇達大街
In Billings, sir, the main street is Minnesota Avenue.
你知道，那個人很當真的
You know, that guy really means business.
- 他讓我很汗 - 我也是
- He had me sweating a little. - Yeah, me too.
- 勞森中尉？ - 是的
- Lieutenant Lawson? - Yes.
有人看見你在J大街的 陸軍消費合作社前，長官
Someone to see you out in front of the PX at J Street, sir.
謝謝，我想會是誰…
Thanks. I wonder who would...
我馬上就來
I'll be right back.
愛倫
Ellen!
你從哪兒來？ 我開到卡羅萊納來給你個驚喜
- Where did you come from? - I drove to Carolina to surprise you.
- 他們告訴我你在這裡 - 是嗎？還好吧
- And then they told me you're down here. - Well, how are you?
湊合，謝謝，你怎麼樣？
I'm just fine, thank you. And how are you bearing up?
還好，你一點都沒變
Oh, great. You look just the same.
當然沒變 你不能總是期望立刻就變
Well, of course I do. You can't expect any change this soon.
- 什麼意思？ - 沒什麼
- What's the joke? - Nothing.
沒想到你這麼搞笑
Except you're so funny.
告訴我親愛的，你驚訝嗎？
Tell me, honey, were you surprised?
我簡直不敢相信我的眼睛 等會兒，我去給你買點喝的
Oh, I couldn't believe my eyes. Here, let me buy you a drink.
真高興見到你
Gee, I'm glad to see you.
來，我們到處走走
Come on, let's go around here.
告訴我甜心，為什麼你這麼可人？
Tell me, honey, how come you're so cute?
我找到了一個如此帥氣的小夥子 我必須得這樣啊
I had to be if I were going to get such a good looking fellow.
我有千言萬語想對你說
You know, there's a lot of things I want to talk over with you.
說吧，你真的很驚訝嗎？
Go ahead. Were you really surprised?
其實不是非常
Well, no, not exactly.
你知道嗎？ 當你睜開雙眼時就會變成這樣
You know, you go into something like this with your eyes open.
- 自然你得抓住機會 - 我知道
- Naturally you've got to take your chances. - I see.
這樣看著它不是有些冷漠嗎？
Isn't that kind of a cold-blooded way to look at it?
快別發瘋了，你真的有點冷漠了
Oh, now, don't get mad. You've got to be cold-blooded about it.
這對我來說是最重要的事
This is the most important thing that's ever happened to me.
- 那我呢？ - 你也是啊
- What about me? - Well, you're in on it, too.
- 這就是我為什麼想說一說的原因 - 真慷慨啊，說吧，特德
- That's why I want to talk it over. - That's very generous. Go on, Ted.
那麼，首先我們得保守秘密
Well, in the first place, we've got to keep it a secret.
- 我也不是要你從心底發誓 - 你是，我是說，你…
- I don't want you to tell a soul. - You're not, I mean, you...
你不希望這一切發生，是嗎？
You don't wish it hadn't happened, do you?
是的，當然
Oh, no, of course not.
但這是軍事機密，我有我的紀律
But it's a military secret, I've got my orders.
軍事…比如，你說的…
Military... Say, what are you talking about?
比如我自願參與的這項任務 你收到我的信了嗎？
Well, this job I volunteered for. Didn't you get my letter?
- 沒有，你收到我的了嗎？ - 沒有
- No. Didn't you get mine? - No.
我覺得這很可笑，但是…
Well, I suppose it's very funny, but...
- 嗨，勞森，特德.勞森 - 到
- Hey, Lawson! Ted Lawson! - Here.
你們藏起來幹什麼？
What are you hiding out...
- 愛倫，什麼時候來的？ - 5分鐘前，我的伴娘還好吧？
- Ellen, when did you get here? - Five minutes ago. How's my bridesmaid?
很好，只是我不得不打斷你們了
Great. Only I'm going to have to break this up.
杜利德來視察我們起飛了
Doolittle came out to watch us take off.
好，晚飯時我來找你
Okay. I'll see you for dinner.
順著路下去一英里半 有家旅館
There's a hotel about a mile and a half down the road.
我還沒去過呢 但他們說你一定能找到的
I haven't seen it yet, but they tell me you can't miss it.
- 我會找到的 - 很抱歉這樣行事匆忙
- I'll find it. - I'm sorry to have to rush off like this.
別忘了晚餐
Don't forget dinner.
有人撿到我的信了嗎？
Say, did anybody pick up a letter for me?
是的，長官 我今早撿到的，我都快忘了
Yes, sir. I did this morning. I forgot all about it.
- 好的，把它拿來 - 是的
- Well, bring it up. - Yes, sir.
對不起，長官
I'm sorry, sir.
好的，謝謝 你來開好嗎，達文波特？
Okay. Thanks. Take over, will you, Davenport.
好的
Sure.
哇，我有孩子了
Hey! I'm going to have a baby!
是愛倫寫的
Hey, it's from Ellen.
她就要是… 我是說，我就要當爸爸了
She's going to be... I mean, I'm going to be a father.
你好，飛行員
Hello, flyer.
對不起叫醒你們
Oh, I'm sorry I woke you up.
我沒睡著，真的 我在假寐冥思
I wasn't sleeping, really. I was just dozing and thinking.
我沒能趕回來吃晚餐，真對不起 我們有太多的檢驗工作
I'm sorry I didn't get back for dinner. We had a lot of checking to do.
你肯定覺得 我今早就是個大笨蛋
You must've thought I was an awful dope this morning.
我直到後來才收到你的信 所以那時我根本不知道
But I didn't get your letter until later, so I didn't know.
我知道，坐吧
I know. Sit down.
孩子的事太美妙了 我知道你會這樣的，我一點也不擔心
- I think it's swell about the baby. - I knew you would. I wasn't a bit worried.
這真好玩
You know, it's going to seem funny.
我不在乎男孩女孩，一點都不重要
I don't care whether it's a boy or a girl. Not that much.
我只要你一切都好，我是認真的
I just want you to be okay. It's pretty serious.
什麼這麼好笑，我剛才在想
- Well, what's so funny? - I was just thinking.
這裡你在準備完成些 非常困難的任務…
Here you're getting ready to go off on something really tough,
那裡還在牽掛著我
and you're worrying about me.
如果我是你，肯定都嚇死了
If I were in your spot, I'd be scared to death.
我覺得我就是這樣的 純粹的例行公事，飛行員
- But I guess I am anyhow. - Purely routine stuff, flyer.
這是每個女孩子生中 都要經的一兩次
The kind of job every girl takes on once or twice in her life.
你為何不躺下？
Why don't you lie down?
你知道嗎，愛倫？
You know, Ellen,
擁有你我已經心滿意足
I'm kind of glad I got you.
我想這就是我剛才睡覺時想的
I guess that's what I was thinking about in my sleep.
快把我嚇住了
It almost frightened me.
就好像我在想 如果我們沒有相遇會怎樣
It seemed that I was thinking, "What if I'd never met him?"
有一點是…
Well, for one thing
你不會遍行全國…
you wouldn't be traipsing around the country
從一個空軍基地到另一個 努力地找我
from one airfield to another trying to catch up with me.
還有就是…
And for another,
你不會在戰爭之際 懷上了一個孩子
you wouldn't be having a baby right in the middle of a war.
不是，不是那樣
Oh, no, it wasn't that.
我在想如果我沒有遇見你…
I was thinking that if I hadn't met you,
我的生命中便沒有人能像你一樣 和我如此親近
I'd never have felt really close to anybody, never in my whole life.
結婚六月，相聚不到兩周
Married six months and together less than two weeks.
這不是我說的親近
That's not being as close as I'd figured on.
特德，你不覺得就是這樣嗎？
Don't you see, Ted, that's just it.
兩人遠在天邊，卻心有所屬…
If people can be close when they're far away from each other,
那才是應該有的
well, that's what it should be.
是是，我也這麼想
Yeah, yeah, I guess so.
抱緊我
Cuddle me.
我想起了上個耶誕節
I was thinking about last Christmas.
在波特蘭汽車旅館 立的那棵聖誕樹
The tree we set up in that Portland auto court.
- 那間屋子不是很小嗎？ - 是啊
- Wasn't it an awful little room? - Yeah.
我們在準備聖誕晚餐
And the Christmas dinner we were planning on.
然後你把煤氣用光了
And then you ran out of gas and landed in the mud up in lllwaco,
我再見你已是耶誕節之後了
Christmas Eve and Christmas were all over before I saw you again.
對，真的很難熬 但無論如何我都挺過來了
Yeah, that was tough. But I got a scarf out of it, anyhow.
這並不和我們的計畫一致
Well, it wasn't exactly as we'd planned it.
這是我們的第一個耶誕節 在一個遙遠地地方
It was our first Christmas, and somewhere way off,
什麼地方不重要
it didn't matter where,
只要我有了你，特德 這是我一生中最美好的一個聖涎
I knew I had you. Oh, Ted, it was the nicest Christmas of my life.
愛倫，你今生註定會嫁給一個飛行員的 從我看見你的第一眼起就這樣想了
You were born to marry a flyer, Ellen. I knew that the minute I first saw you.
事實上，這就是我嫁給你的理由
As a matter of fact that's why I married you.
- 我想對你說句告白 - 什麼？
- You know, I've got a confession to make. - What?
事實是，不是你娶了我 是我嫁給了你
The truth is, you didn't marry me. I married you.
是嗎？
Oh, you did, eh?
我在洛杉礬城市學院國書館 第一次看見你…
The first time I saw you in the library at LACC,
我就對自己說：噢，他會是我的
I said to myself, "Oh, oh, that's for me."
從那時起
And from then on,
從那一個個美好的夜晚 到離開那個愛荷達的小鎮
clear up to the night we got the judge out of bed in that little Idaho town,
沒有什麼是偶然，特德
nothing was an accident, Ted.
都是我設計的
I planned it that way.
- 你覺得你很聰慧，是嗎？ - 我自己也不確定
- You think you're pretty smart, don't you? - I'm not sure whether I do or not.
你瞧，你並沒有表現出 十足的戰鬥力
You see, you didn't put up much of a fight.
我想你也在考慮孩子
I suppose you figured out on that baby, too?
那是你根本不可能知道的 飛行員根本不知道
That's something you'll never know, flyer, you'll never know.
這幾天小夥子們都熬得很晚啊
Boys are working late these nights.
是啊，你認為你們會離開多久？
Yes. Do you have any idea how long you'll be gone?
但只要任務結束 我就會去要求一個假期
But as soon as this job is over, I'm going to ask for a leave.
也許兩到三周
Two, maybe three weeks.
我們可以度蜜月了 以前你不是總提起嗎？
We'll have that honeymoon you're always talking about.
是的，就我們仨
Yes, just the three of us.
特德
Ted.
我真希望我不要長得又肥又醜 就像芝加哥肥婆一樣
I do hope I don't get big and fat like that lady in Chicago.
我想要你們每個人都知道一些 其他人的工作
I want each one of you to know something about the other man's job.
飛行員會擔負飛機上的一切任務
The pilots will practice every job on the plane.
導航員要學學投彈手的工作 等等
Navigators will learn the work of bombardiers and so forth.
以防你們當中有人被擊中
That's in case any of you get shot up.
還有一件事
There's one thing more.
不可避免的事 你們當中的某些飛機…
It is inevitable that some of your planes
會落入敵人手中
are going to fall into the hands of the enemy.
出於這樣的考慮，我命令你們 拆掉諾登投彈瞄準器
For this reason, I have ordered your Norden bombsights removed.
格裡甯上校研發了一種瞄準器 很適合你們的
Captain Greening has designed a sight which will be perfect for our job.
如果沒什麼問題了 那麼就請約克上校來說說
If there are no questions, I'll ask Captain York to take over.
剛才我說過，我們去巴西巡邏
Just like I said, we patrol off Brazil.
那麼為什麼我們要拆掉 諾登投彈瞄準器？
Yeah, but what about taking the Norden Bombsight out?
如果我們是去打擊潛艇的話 根本不可能被敵機擊中
There's no chance of falling into the hands of the enemy if you're hunting subs.
我從不那樣認為 那都是杜利德的鬼話，是吧？
- I hadn't thought of that. - That Doolittle's a cheerful cuss, isn't he?
以防你們當中有人被擊中 被燦爛的陽光擊中
"Just in case any of us are shot up," a bundle of sunshine.
哦，那是特德，特德
Oh, it's Ted, it's Ted!
我們第一次結婚時 喬治也這樣嗡嗡從我身邊開過
George used to buzz me when we were first married.
他再也不那樣了，這是不允許的
He doesn't do it any more. They're not supposed to.
我懷疑他是否還愛我 我可一點也不擔心
- I wonder if he still loves me. - I wouldn't worry about that.
每次斯基有了一架新飛機 就像愛上了它似的
Every time Ski gets a new ship he has a terrible love affair with it,
但他總會回到我身邊的
but he always comes back to me,
尤其是當他餓得咕咕叫時
especially when he's hungry.
想想看他們會離開三個月
Just think, they'll be gone three months.
我想我會在國防工廠 找到一份工作
I think I'll get a job in a defense factory.
我真的不能忍受坐在一間小公寓 無盡等待，無所事事
I couldn't stand just sitting around in some little apartment and waiting.
你打算怎麼辦，愛倫？
What are you going to do, Ellen?
我想靜下心來，因為我有孩子了
Oh, I'm just going to sit around and have a baby.
- 一個孩子 - 一個孩子
- A baby! - A baby!
愛倫，為什麼不告訴我們？
Ellen, why didn't you tell us?
我不知道，或許我一直沒想好怎麼說 直到剛才
I don't know. I guess I just never thought of a way till now.
既然這樣了，說說也不難啊
As it turns out, it wasn't hard to tell at all.
我也有了一個孩子了
Well, I'm going to have one, too.
是麼，真的嗎？
- What? - Really?
我覺得這樣太棒了
Gee, I think it's wonderful.
喬治和我商量過的，但現在他走了…
George and I have talked about it, but, well, with him away and all,
- 我想我可能太害怕了 - 我也害怕，但是…
- I guess I'm just too scared. - I thought I would be too, but...
特德和我猜想 珍珠港事件後的每一件事…
Well, Ted and I figured that everything since Pearl Harbor
都如此順利
has just been so much velvet.
我想如果他發生了什麼事…
And then I guessed that if anything should happen to him,
我知道不會發生的
only I know nothing will,
我就會把小孩生下來 這就是特德仍然活著的希望
I'd have the baby, and that would be a little bit of Ted still living.
我有時想知道，等一切都結束了 我們會怎樣
I sometimes wonder how we'll feel when it's all over.
在某個地方安頓下來 找一件小房子…
Just think, being able to settle down in a little house somewhere
撫養你們的小孩，無憂無慮
and raise your children and never be in doubt about anything.
我對現在的生活…
We'll probably have exactly the same doubts
倒想打一個問號
that we have right now.
比如，他會回來吃晚飯嗎？
For example, will he or will he not be home for dinner?
我們將要進行本次訓練中 最機密的一部分
We're about to enter the most secret part of our training.
機場周邊都部署了巡邏 所以沒人能打擾你們
This field is patrolled on all sides so no one can disturb you at your work.
同志們，這是米勒海軍上尉
Gentlemen, this is Lieutenant Miller of the Navy.
他將指示你們的起飛
He's going to instruct you in takeoffs.
除了正常的B-25在1500英尺內 以90英里的時速起飛…
Instead of the normal B-25 takeoff in 1,500 feet at 90 miles an hour,
他還會教你們…
he's going to show you how to do it
全負荷炸彈和汽油時，在500英尺內 以50英里的時速起飛
with a full load of bombs and gas in 500 feet at 50 miles an hour.
你們將嘗試短距離起飛
You will attempt no short takeoffs
從埃格林空軍基地 大家都可以看到
from Eglin Field, where people can see you.
米勒海軍上尉還會給你們一些 海軍禮儀講座
Lieutenant Miller will also give you a few short talks on naval etiquette.
如果我說的這些讓你們覺察到了 有關你們的目的地…
Now, if this gives you any hints as to your destination
和此次任務的蛛絲馬跡…
or as to what kind of work you're going to do,
不要在下麵議論
don't even discuss it among yourselves.
接下來的時間交給米勒海軍上尉
I'll ask Lieutenant Miller to take over now.
先生們
Gentlemen,
這些旗子距離起點有…
those flags out there are at 100, 200, 300, 400, and 500 feet
100、200、300、400和500英里遠
from the starting line.
訓練場中間的這些線 是引導你們起飛的
The line down the center of the field is to guide you in your takeoff.
你們的任務不允許有任何的背離
The kind of work you're going to do won't permit any deviations.
記住，叫離開踏板前勁踩足了
Now, the whole idea is to get up full power before you release your brakes.
然後開始以最大轉率加壓
Then start, at maximum r.p.m., manifold pressure
讓機翼側翼立起來
and with your wing flaps all the way down.
你們要加快電機轉率 直到你認為它快要燃燒起來為止
You'll have to rev your motors until you think they're going to burn up.
然後如果它們向右傾斜
And then, when they reach the right pitch,
聲音和感覺比指令更重要
and that's a matter of sound and feel more than instruments,
放開?車去見上帝吧
release your brakes and hunt for heaven.
我不想你們第一次都去嘗試這樣
I don't expect any of you to do it the first time.
- 格雷 - 到
- Gray. - Yes, sir.
你和門奇是不是想第一個試試
Suppose you and Manch try it first?
剩下的人待在裡面 評判你們的表現，觀測一下風速
The rest of us will stay on the ground, mark your takeoff and check the wind.
是
Yes, sir.
我覺得最開始我們可以 從觀看、試飛中學到…
I think at first we can learn as much by watching trial runs
和實際飛行一樣多的東西
as by actually flying the ships.
那麼我們就在這裡排好隊 看看他們怎麼表現
So let's all line up over here and see how he does.
- 地表風速怎樣，斯基？ - 每小時8英里
- What kind of surface wind, Ski? - Eight miles an hour.
他沒有把引擎轉速提升到足夠快
He didn't have his engines revved up enough.
勞森，你接著去
Lawson, you go next.
記住，我們的目的是
Now remember, for our purposes,
如果你把你的一個輪子飛離地面 就足夠好了
if you get your wheels a foot off the ground, that's good enough.
不需要太高 但一定要讓輪子離開地面
You don't need height, but you've got to get your wheels off
但不至於碰到旗子
before you hit the last flag.
等一會兒我們會嘗試 在450英里內收回輪子
A little later we'll try retracting the wheels at around 450 feet
全靠你們的發動機支撐
and relying on your motors to float the ship.
- 但不要那樣做 - 好的，長官
- Don't try that just yet, though. - Right, sir.
抓住控制杆用力拉 直到你有了堅定的信心了
Now, grab the column and pull her until you feel the inside of your backbone.
好的，長官
Yes, sir.
你駕駛過B-25在500英尺內起飛嗎 長官
Did you ever take off a B-25 at 500 feet, sir?
沒有，但是你們可以別擔心
No. But you men will. Don't worry about it.
看看勞森
Watch Lawson there.
你們至少得把發動機轉速 提到那樣高，甚至更高
You'll have to rev your motors at least that high and maybe higher.
大約7oo英尺，他燒掉了他的尾撬 沒有來得及收起輪子
About 700 feet. He burned his tailskid. Didn't pull his wheels up soon enough.
嘿，剛才的起飛真是虛驚一場啊
Brother, that takeoff was strictly on the cob.
你的飛機真像一隻撕碎的鴨子
That airplane of yours looked exactly like a ruptured duck.
你覺得它怎麼樣？
How do you like this guy?
他起飛就像一個年邁的女土 頂著狂風
He takes off like an old lady in a high wind,
終於鼓起勇氣 試試真正的飛機了
and then he's got the nerve to talk about a real ship.
你真走運沒有在一個泥濘的機場 不然你還會在這兒
It's lucky you didn't have a muddy field, or you'd still be there.
我一點都不擔心那個 你和格雷確實在忸怩作態
If I were you I'd worry about that turkey you and Gray are pushing around the sky.
撕裂的“鴨子”一切安好 我被侮辱了，走吧，兄弟們
- The ruptured duck will get along okay. - Oh, I'm insulted. Come on, fellows.
不會修很長時間的，先生
That won't take long to fix, sir.
撕裂的“鴨子”
Ruptured duck.
特德
Ted.
如果是個女孩 琳達這個名字怎麼樣？
Don't you think Linda's a good name, if it's a girl?
好，很好
Oh, yes, yes, it's fine.
不，也許是尼古拉 尼古拉
No, maybe Nichola. Nichola?
聽起來很悅耳，是吧？
That has a nice sound, don't you think?
什麼？對對
What's that? Oh, yes.
親愛的，我們不要著急 現在就決定吧
Look, honey, we don't have to decide that right now, do we?
不用
No.
特德
Ted.
他傷得不重吧？
He wasn't badly hurt, was he?
- 誰？ - 約翰尼.亞當斯
- Who? - Johnny Adams.
- 你怎麼知道約翰尼的？ - 都傳開了
- How'd you hear about Johnny? - Those things get around.
- 他沒有吧？ - 當然沒有
- He wasn't hurt, was he? - Of course not.
我不知道是怎麼發生的
I don't know how those things get started.
每個在這個基地打聽出來的消息 總要被吹捧一番
Every time a guy does a noseover on this field, it's a crack-up.
特德
Ted.
你晚飯後就一直在忙 來，我們出去走走
You've been working ever since dinner. Come on, let's get some air.
不錯
It's a deal.
真美
Nice.
很抱歉，我們不能有 更多的時間在一起，艾倫
I'm sorry we haven't had more time together, Ellen.
我們現在的時間很少 但以後都是我們的
We can spare a little. We've got all the rest of our lives.
對
That's right.
什麼東西開花了 好香啊，是吧？
Something blooming? It smells good, doesn't it?
- 特德 - 什麼？
- Ted. - What?
求你了，不要胡思亂想
Please, don't worry about anything.
我沒有擔心 我只是在工作，僅此而己
I'm not worrying, just working, that's all.
這次的任務非常重要
You know, this is going to be quite a deal.
你不是在擔心你的任務 你擔心因為你有一個妻子
You're not worried about the deal. You're worried because you've got a wife.
那是錯的，特德
And that's wrong, Ted.
鮑勃格雷沒有來嚇唬你吧？
Say, Bob Gray hasn't been trying to scare you, has he?
- 當然沒有 - 那就好
- Of course not. - Okay.
因為沒什麼好擔心的，沒什麼
Because there's nothing to worry about, nothing.
傻瓜，我就裝作不知道
Silly, as if I didn't know that.
還有，如果發生了什麼 你會得到政府保險的全部
Besides, if anything did happen, you've got all that government insurance,
這樣我就能照顧你和孩子 很長一段時間了
that'll take care of you and the baby for a long while.
天哪，我們在說什麼 無論如何也不會發生什麼的
Oh, what am I talking about? Nothing's going to happen anyhow.
特德，看著我
Ted, look at me.
孩子和我不需要任何東西 除了你
That baby and I, we won't ever need anything but you.
我們誰都不准害怕，特德
We mustn't either of us be scared about it, Ted.
因為我們的孩子 是我堅信你會回來的理由
Because the baby, the baby's why I know you're coming back to us.
這次我們做好一點 不然就再也聽不到這樣的聲音了
We'd better make this one, or Shorty'll never let us hear the last of it.
好
Yeah.
聽到那些引擎了嗎？ 就像音樂一樣
- Hear those engines? - Like music.
來吧，你們這些有前途的巴土司機
Come on, you hopped up bus drivers.
十個星期以來的一個狂歡夜 來吧
It's been 10 weeks work and one night's fun. Let's go.
我把側翼立起來了，兄弟們 燃燒吧，勇敢者們
- I got my flaps up, brother. - Heat it up there, Smitty boy.
蒸汽的絲絲聲你們要去哪 沒有人攔你
Steam and sizzle. Where you're going, no one's gonna hold you tight.
嗨，多克，知道怎麼跳舞嗎？
Hey there, Doc, don't you know how to dance?
當別人拿走你的高射炮時
When they start picking flak out of your feet,
你應該慶倖它會得到更好的利用
you'll wish you'd put them to better use.
我是醫生 不是爵士舞迷，肖特
I'm a doctor, not a jitterbug, Shorty.
- 嗨，這是在做什麼？ - 肖特組織的的派對
- Hey, what gives? - Shorty's throwing a party.
派對？為什麼？
A party? What for?
有人說他是在慶祝得州憲法日
Somebody said he's celebrating Texas Constitution Day.
得州憲法日？ 那麼我也得試一下
- Texas Constitution Day? - Say, I'm gonna sample this.
找個女孩吧，勞森
Grab your gal, Lawson.
不知道今天是 山姆.休士頓的生日嗎？
Don't you know it's Sam Houston's birthday?
山姆.休士頓
Sam Houston?
一個從未到過得州的人 門奇經常說起
For a guy that never saw Texas, that Manch is really sold.
- 你好，勞森 - 你好啊，怎麼想起這麼放蕩的？
- Hi, Lawson. - Hi. How did this riot get started?
今天是得州加入聯邦紀念日
It's Texas Admission Day.
這不是放蕩先生 這是一場已然的戰爭
And that ain't no riot, mister, that's a full-fledged war.
- 看見艾倫了嗎？ - 我誰都看見過的
- Seen Ellen? - I've seen everybody.
你好，飛行員，和我跳舞
- Hello, flyer. - My dance?
當然啊，我的心上人
All of them, my boy.
此刻起的每一隻舞，直至最後
Every dance from now on out, including the last one.
我愛你，斯基 我愛你
And I love you, Ski. I love you, I love you, I love you.
這真搞笑 勞森以前居然和一架得州飛機…
You know, it's a funny thing. That Lawson used to be about as graceful
一樣高雅，快瞧他
as a Texas steer. Now, look at him.
也許是那個女孩的緣故
Maybe the girl's got something to do with it.
你說上次，克勒文…
Ah, you said it that time, Clever.
有些事我打算告訴你更多
You know, there's something I mean to tell you more often,
- 但我一直沒找到機會 - 什麼事？
- but I never seem to get the chance. - What is it?
我愛你
Just that I love you.
我今天收到了你母親的一封信 忘了告訴你
I got a letter from your mother this morning. Forgot to tell you.
她說你要自己照顧好自己
She said to take good care of you.
那我怎麼樣 媽媽做夢也不會想到的好
- How am I doing? - Better than mother ever dreamed of.
好了，好了
Here. Here.
笑一笑，唱啊
Now smile and sing.
特德
Ted.
電話響了
Telephone's ringing.
- 電話，特德 - 好的
- Telephone, Ted. - Oh, sure.
是嗎，現在？好的
Yeah? Right now? Okay.
好
Okay.
行
什麼事？
What was it?
是一次夜間召集 但這是一個美妙的夜晚
Oh, just another night call. But what a night.
對不起
I'm sorry.
幾點了？
What time is it?
3:10
3:10.
- 心裡難受嗎？ - 沒什麼，只是頭痛病
- Hung-over maybe a little? - Oh, just a headache.
- 我不大適應派對的氣氛 - 可憐的寶貝
- I'm not used to party life. - Poor baby.
你應該睡覺了，我早飯前趕回來
You go to sleep. I'll be back by breakfast time.
我很困了，晚安，親愛的
I'm so sleepy. Goodnight, darling.
或者說早安
Or rather, good morning.
如果我得到一個假期 我要整整睡上六天
Boy, if I ever get a leave, I'm going to sleep for six days solid.
不知道又是什麼
I wonder what this is.
同志們，你們的飛機檢修好了 加滿油了，準備起飛
Well, men, your ships are all serviced, gassed, and ready to go.
你們將輪流起飛
You will take off in shifts,
一班45分鐘
the first shift taking off in 45 minutes.
約克上校會給你們准飛的指示
Captain York will give you your clearances.
有一件事必須清楚
Now there's one thing that must be thoroughly understood.
今早起飛後
After you take off this morning,
你們不允許見到任何人、和任何人說話打電話 甚至是你們的妻子
you are to see no one, speak to no one, telephone no one, not even your wife.
沒有例外
There are no exceptions.
繼續你們到達目的地的油耗測試
Continue your gas consumption tests to your destination.
你們的任務要求低海拔飛行
Now, the work you will be asked to do will require a little low altitude flying,
所以超低空飛行是完全可以的
so hedge-hopping on this trip is perfectly okay.
記住，牛仔們總是戴高帽子
Only bear in mind that cowboys wear pretty tall hats,
所以小心一點，就這樣
so watch your step, men. That's all.
我想你們已經為你們自願參加的任務 作好了準備
I think you're very well prepared for what you volunteered to do
我要感謝你們辛勤而出色的表現
and I want to thank you for a lot of good hard work.
幾天後再見，祝你們好運
I'll see you in a few days. Good luck.
我想找個機會和艾倫說再見
I hope I get a chance to tell Ellen goodbye.
你會有的
Yeah, you will.
你們的目的地是 阿拉梅達空軍基地
Your destination is Alameda field.
走南方航線在聖安東尼奧補給 然後前進
Take the southern route, refuel at San Antonio and march.
點到名後就可以開始了 第一個，霍爾斯通
As your names are called you can start. First flight, Holstrom,
鐘斯 勞森，第二個
Jones, Lawson. Second flight...
- 特德 - 好了，寶貝，我要走了
- Ted. - Well, this is it, honey. We're off.
什麼時候？ 只有時間收收東西了
- How soon? - Just got time to pack.
我的B-4包在哪裡？
Where's my B-4 bag?
- 在壁櫥裡，我去拿 - 好的
- In the closet. I'll get it. - Good.
襪子、襯衣
Socks, shirts.
- 我的領帶也在壁櫥 - 是的，我去拿
- My ties in the closet? - Yes, I have them.
好的
Good.
哇，不要光著腳走進去 我打碎了個杯子
Wow! Don't go in there in your bare feet, I broke a glass.
好的
All right.
- 你忘了你的牙刷 - 見鬼
- You forgot your toothbrush. - Oh, doggone it.
- 都收好了嗎？ - 差不多了
- We got everything? - I think so.
好樣的
Swell.
好的，做一個好女孩 照顧好孩子
Well, be a good girl and take good care of that baby.
我會的，特德，照顧好你自己
- I will, Ted. - Yourself, too.
特德，你走後的每一天 我都會給你寫一封信
Oh, Ted, I'm going to write you a letter every day you're gone,
我知道他們不會送達 我也不會寄出的
I know they won't deliver them. I won't even mail them.
但我還是要寫 這樣我們就能保持聯繫了
But I'm going to write just the same. That way, we'll kind of be in touch.
我們就能感覺到彼此的鼻息
That way, we'll feel close.
再見
Goodbye.
再見，飛行員
Bye, flyer.
告訴我甜心，為什麼你這麼可人？
Tell me, honey. How come you're so cute?
我找到了一個如此帥氣的小夥子 我必須得這樣啊
I had to be if I was gonna get such a good looking fellow.
我會回來的
I'll be back.
嘿，海灣大橋正從我們的右側離開
Hey, the Bay Bridge is off to our right.
The Bay Bridge is off to our right.
海灣大橋，從它下面飛過怎樣？
The Bay Bridge? How about flying under it?
- 為什麼？ - 那樣的話我可以照些照片
- For why? - Well, so I can get some pictures.
從下往上拍攝這些超級建築
You know, shooting up at the superstructure.
來吧，勞森 不想嗎？
- Come on, Lawson. - Do you want to?
好的，走吧 如果我可以讓他高興  謝謝
- Sure. Go ahead, if it'll make him happy. - Thanks.
希望那個跨度裡沒有纜繩
I hope there are no cables hanging under that span.
走
Here we go.
讓我們輪流來一次 我忘了放膠捲了
Let's take a turn and go it again. I forgot to put film in.
我們要去基地別忘了
We're due at the field. Forget it.
我再也不想試了
Oh, I may never get another crack at it.
嘿，快看
Hey, look.
麥克盧爾，看下麵
McClure, take a look down there.
是航空母艦 是啊，你看他的艦板
- It's a carrier. - Yeah. And look at her deck.
B-25的，神聖煙霧就是它了
B-25's. Holy Smoke. Then this is it.
有點小，是吧？
Kind of small, isn't she?
飛行員呼叫投彈手 飛行員呼叫炮手
Pilot to bombardier. Pilot to gunner. Pilot to gunner.
柴契爾、柴契爾
Thatcher. Thatcher.
又斷了
It's dead again.
到達以後 我們最後給杜利德報告一下
We'd better report it to Doolittle when we get in.
對，還有左引擎 對你來說還那樣討厭嗎？
Yeah, that left engine along with it. Still seem a little rough to you?
我不想說了
I can't tell anymore.
- 你們的飛機沒事吧？ - 什麼？沒事沒事，長官
- Is everything okay on your ship? - Why, yes, sir, yes, sir.
計程車已經在航母碼頭了 他們會照顧好你們的
Taxi over to the edge of the carrier's wharf. They'll take care of you there.
好的，長官
Yes, sir.
他們也不等人家下車
They don't even wait until a fellow gets out.
所有的海軍都是這樣自以為是 米勒就是海軍
- All Navy guys are cocky. - Miller's a Navy guy.
米勒其實不是海軍，他是飛行員
Well, Miller isn't exactly Navy. He's a pilot.
喂，飛行員
Hey, Spike.
飛行員 飛行員 什麼事？
- Spike. - Spike, what's the matter?
我在抱怨我的燃油泵
Oh, I put in a beef about my fuel pump
杜利德叫我把它送到 飛機修理棚去
and Doolittle told me to take her to the hangar.
你不去？
Well, then you're not going?
不去，其實飛機沒什麼毛病
No, and there's nothing really wrong with that plane.
這是我們班最好的飛機 兄弟，別大意
- It's the best ship in the squad. - Boy, that's rough.
我正準備告訴他我們的對講機
And I nearly told him about our interphone.
你真是個無可救藥的人
You would've been a cooked goose.
我也覺得我去看看那些海軍
I think, sir, I'll go and watch those Navy guys.
- 他們會摔壞的 - 想得不錯
- They might bang her up or something. - That's a good idea.
你覺得呢？
How do you like that?
他們肯定會把“鴨子”弄壞
They're going to break the Duck's back sure.
我們怎麼從那些海軍手裡 弄到離合器
How did we get in the clutches of these Navy guys anyhow?
- 你們看，這真是一艘大船 - 是的，去看看
- Boy, that's an awful big ship. - Yeah, let's take a look at her.
再見，飛行員 再見，飛行員
- So long, Spike. - So long, Spike.
再見，飛行員 再見，夥計們
- Be seeing you, Spike. - Goodbye, fellows.
勞森中尉 報告，長官
Lieutenant Lawson, reporting aboard, sir.
- 伯廷勒，把勞森中尉帶到… - 306，長官
- Bettinger, take Lieutenant Lawson to... - 306, sir.
306 這邊走，先生
- 306. - This way, sir.
待會見
See you guys later.
- 麥克盧爾中尉 - 報告，長官
Lieutenant McClure, reporting aboard, sir.
這是你們的住處，先生
These are your quarters, sir.
懷特和費爾頓先生正在上岸假期中
Mr. White and Mr. Felton are on shore leave.
謝謝
Thank you.
你確定能找到回到甲板的路嗎，先生？
Are you sure you'll be able to find your way back up to the deck, sir?
是的，謝謝
Oh, sure. Thanks.
你在做什麼？
What are you doing down here?
隨便逛逛，你呢？
Oh, just looking around. What are you doing here?
隨便逛逛
Just looking around.
你也迷路了 是嗎？我就像一隻被逮住的老鼠
- Are you lost too? - Am I lost? I'm trapped like a rat.
我已經走了幾英里了
I've been walking for miles.
這是我見過的最大的船
This is the biggest cockeyed ship I've ever seen.
是啊，我希望甲板能有兩倍這麼大
Yeah. And I wish the deck was twice as big.
吸煙燈已滅，吸煙燈已滅
The smoking lamp is out. The smoking lamp is out.
先生，吸煙燈已滅 意思是船上禁止吸煙
Sir, "The smoking lamp is out" means no smoking anywhere on the ship.
好的，為什麼？
- Okay. - Why is that?
因為正在補給燃料 先生，他們會告訴我們什麼時候結束
Because they're refueling, sir. They'll let us know when they're through.
你好
Hello.
你們終於來了
Well, you guys finally got on, huh?
對，我們在看看這個浴盆
Yeah, we've just been looking the tub over.
- 你們住得怎樣？ - 很不錯
- How are your quarters? - Perfect.
有兩個鋪位和帆布床
Nice room with two bunks and a cot.
帆布床，跟我來，兄弟們 我讓你們看看真正的房間
A cot? Follow me, brothers. I'm gonna show you real quarters.
我是說寢室
And I mean quarters.
帽子 帽子
Hats. Hats.
- 看，這是什麼？ - 我們有客人來了
- Well, look at what's here. - Well, we have guests.
為什麼把大家 從棚戶租賃區趕到這兒？
What's the idea of bringing people up here from the tenement district?
這裡被戲謔地叫做“旗艦艙”
This is jocularly known as the admiral's cabin.
你們的洗澡時間快到了
Looks like you guys are going to have to start bathing.
還沒完呢，還有其他的，跟我走
This isn't all. There's something else. Follow me.
非常樂意
I'd be glad to.
請當心那些地毯
Careful of the rugs, please.
裡面的東西，先生們 可以讓你們大飽眼福
Now just inside, gentlemen, is something to really feast your peepers on.
晚飯後第一個回來的人 才有機會看到
The first guy turns in after dinner gets this bed for the trip.
你知道是誰嗎？ 進來
You know who that'll be. Enter.
哪來的又髒又噁心的… 快滾蛋，你這個橡皮蟲
What dirty, lowlife... Come out of there, you boll weevil!
好吧，那給我吃玉米 讓我快快長大
Well, feed me corn and watch me grow.
這些渣滓是怎麼進來的？
How did all this scum get in?
我是在一張海軍帆布床
And me in an Army cot.
今晚結束你死定了
That's where he'll end up, before the night's over.
- 我們走 - 噢，上尉
- Let's get out of here. - Oh, Lieutenant!
你們去吃晚飯時
When you guys go down to dinner,
能帶給我一份半熟的 烤牛肉三明治…
would you mind bringing back a roast beef sandwich, rare,
和一份橘子派嗎，上尉？
and a piece of huckleberry pie, Lieutenant.
- 現在你還覺得來這裡不錯嗎？ - 當然，你不是嗎？
- Well, are you still glad you came along? - Sure. Aren't you?
我的感覺怪怪的
- I've got a funny feeling about this job. - Yeah?
我覺得可能事情沒有 我們想像的那樣有把握
I think maybe it isn't going to be as much of a cinch as we figured on.
我也這樣想過
Yeah, I've been thinking the same thing.
我的飛機在那裡，我們去看看吧
Well, my ship's over there. I think I'll go take a look at it.
鴨子，在上面 明早見
Well, the Duck's up ahead. I'll see you in the morning.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
是誰？
Who's that?
- 是你嗎，柴契爾？ - 是的，長官
- That you, Thatcher? - Oh, yes, sir.
算了吧，柴契爾
Oh, forget it, Thatcher.
這些東西拴緊了吧？
Got her pretty well lashed down, haven't they?
是的，他們幹得不錯
Yes, sir. They did a good job.
我有點擔心它
I was kind of worried about her,
所以我想上去看看它
so I thought I'd better come up and have a look.
你寂寞嗎？
You lonesome?
我想大家都有點
I guess everybody is a little, sir.
不要讓領導操心 大衛，你的住處還不錯吧？
Don't bother with the sirs, Dave. Your quarters all right?
- 是的，很好 - 吃得也很好，不是嗎？
- Yeah. Fine. - Grub's good, too, isn't it?
很長時間都沒吃到這麼好了
The best I've had in a long time, sir.
回去後怎麼打算，柴契爾？
What are you going to do when we get back home, Thatcher?
我在比令斯有個女孩，長官 如果能回去我會和她結婚
Oh, I have a girl in Billings, sir. I'm going to marry her, if we get back.
我們會平安返回的
Oh, we'll get back all right.
你好
Oh, hello.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
我本來想上來拍幾張星星的 但霧太大了
I thought I'd come up and shoot the stars for a little while, but I guess it's too foggy.
太多霧了，確實
Pretty foggy, all right.
- 你們在這兒做什麼？ - 就是想呼吸點新鮮空氣
- What are you guys doing here? - Oh, just getting a little air.
- 下麵太無聊了 - 的確如此
- Yeah, it's pretty stuffy down below. - Yeah, it sure is.
你們這些人還擔心這個撕裂的鴨子 就像一群老處女一樣
You guys worry over the ruptured duck like a bunch of old maids.
我想睡覺了
Me, I'm going to bed.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
晚安，特德
Goodnight, Ted.
空氣不錯，是吧？
Wonderful air, isn't it?
吸煙燈己亮，吸煙燈己亮
The smoking lamp is lit. The smoking lamp is lit.
- 怎麼了？發生什麼了？ - 戰位
- What's wrong? What happened? - Just battle stations.
日落和日出的時候 這個大東西總會給我們惹麻煩
Around sunup and sundown the pig boats give us a little trouble
所以我們總是靜靜等他
so we always lay for them.
這是吉格.懷特 這是巴德.費爾頓
This is Jig White and I'm Bud Felton.
很高興見到你 很高興見到你
- Glad to see you. - Glad to see you.
- 你好 - 待會見
- How are you? - See you later.
我們是在航行中嗎？ 還有5個小時
- Are we underway? - For the last five hours.
很高興和你同住，士兵
Glad to have you aboard, Army.
總部命令請戰位
General Quarters, man your battle stations.
軍隊人員，請準備你們的飛機
Army personnel, man your planes.
你們唯一可以逃離這裡的方式 是找一個起重機
Boy, the only way you're going to get that thing off of here is with a crane.
也許是，但我也在想 我們可以借助自己的力量起飛
Maybe so. But we kind of think we can take off on our own power.
嘿，他們打哪兒來？
Hey, where'd they come from?
他們是護衛隊
That's what's known as an escort.
晚上他們已經跟著我們了
They just slipped up on us during the night.
海軍總愛秘密行事
The Navy likes to do things quietly.
好像就要有一場表演似的，是吧？
Looks like it's really going to be a show, doesn't it?
我今天真不想讓我離開床單 那張床太舒服了
Boy, did I hate to part skin from sheet this morning. What a bed.
這是肖特.門奇、吉格.懷特 和巴德.費爾頓
Oh, this is Shorty Manch. Jig White and Bud Felton.
嗨，你們好
- Hello. - Hi y'all.
他們很幸運 可以不在“船艦艙“裡睡黨
This lucky stiff is sleeping in the bedroom off the admiral's cabin.
是啊，住得很棒，就是無所事事
Yeah. Wonderful accommodations, but nothing much to do.
我覺得至少應該來點紙牌 或是其他什麼遊戲
I thought there'd at least be a poker game or something going on.
我想他們時不時會玩的
Oh, I guess they have them every once in a while.
“七趾皮特”呢？你們這兒玩嗎？
How about Seven-Toed Pete? Do you ever play much of that around here?
什麼“七趾皮特”？
What's Seven-Toed Pete?
這是一種七張牌的遊戲
Well, it's a kind of seven-card poker.
- 我有時間會教你們 - 從未聽說過
- I'd be glad to teach it to you some time. - Never heard of it.
全軍注意
Attention, Army personnel!
全軍注意 在守衛室集合
Attention, Army personnel! Assemble in Ward Room.
全軍注意，在守衛室集合
- See you later, fellows. - Assemble in Ward Room.
大家好，很榮幸見到大家 我們很快就會在一起了
Well, it's been a great pleasure, fellows. We'll certainly have to get together soon.
也許我們可以玩那個撲克遊戲了
Maybe we can get up that little game of poker.
待會見
See you later.
我相信他很愛玩那個撲克遊戲
You know, I believe that boy wants to play poker.
我在想他是不是上船前 帶足了錢的
I wonder if they got their pay before they came aboard.
請坐
As you were.
你們不是還有剩下的疑慮嗎？
For the benefit of those who haven't already guessed,
我們正在前往日本
we're going straight to Japan.
海軍會把我們送到 距離日本本土400英里的地方
The Navy will take us within 400 miles of the Japanese mainland.
我們會襲擊日本的東京、橫濱
We're going to bomb Tokyo, Yokohama,
神戶、大阪、名古屋
Kobe, Osaka, Nagoya.
這是一次夜間行動
It'll be a night job and
你們可以選擇 你們想去的地方
you will be given the opportunity of choosing the city you prefer.
現在的處境很困難
Now, this is going to be a tight squeeze.
中國軍隊準備在日佔領區 開闢小規模戰場
The Chinese have prepared small fields just outside of Japanese occupied territory
我們則在空襲後登陸
for us to land on after the raid.
他們會給我們補給 然後我們飛往重慶
They'll gas us up and we'll take off for Chungking.
現在起我們將會處在 敵人不斷攻擊的危險中
From now on we're in constant danger of enemy attack.
如果發生地面攻擊
If there should be a surface attack,
站在你們的飛機旁，帶著滅火器
stand by your planes with fire extinguishers
讓海軍去對付他們
and let the Navy handle it.
如果發生了空中攻擊 起飛飛向最近的陸地
If there should be an attack by air, take off and make for the nearest land.
海軍會提供導航資訊 兩天一次
The Navy will give all navigators their bearings twice a day.
再有就是，我還要強調…
Now once more, I want to emphasize that if...
如果有人覺得無法勝任此次任務 完全可以自動請退
If any of you feel you're not up to this job, it's perfectly all right for you to drop out.
我們有一些後備人員 他們可以填補你們的位置
We have a few spare men and I think we can fill your place.
約克上校會告訴你們 用飛機來幹什麼
Get together with Captain York and find out what to do with your planes.
明天下午2:30我們再見
We'll meet here tomorrow afternoon at 2:30.
有問題嗎？
Are there any questions?
上校，集合時可以抽煙嗎？
Colonel, do you mind if we smoke during these assemblies?
如果海軍不反對，我沒有異議 還有什麼嗎？
I have no objection to that if the Navy hasn't. Anything else?
解散
Dismissed.
48、49、50
48, 49, 50.
51、52、53、54
51, 52, 53, 54,
55、56…對不起，門奇
55, 56... Oh, sorry, Manch.
- 在運動 - 是嗎？我可沒有
- Just getting a little exercise. - Yeah? Well, I wasn't.
我在劃分這個巨大的甲板
I'm measuring off this cockeyed deck.
9…
Nine...
全軍注意，你們很想知道 我們此次任務的情況
Attention, all personnel. You have been wondering about the mission we are on.
我想你們肯定知道
I think you might like to know
大黃蜂正開赴日本準備轟炸
that the Army personnel on the Hornet are going to bomb Japan.
我們海軍將要把他們送達 離敵人最近的地方
We of the Navy are going to take them in as close to the enemy as possible.
這是我們大家的機會
This is a chance for all of us
給倭人一點顏色看看
to give the Japs a dose of their own medicine.
這是一場空海軍表演
It's an Army-Navy show.
讓我們真誠歡迎這些將士們
Let's extend every courtesy to the Army men on the Hornet
他們將執行這次的任務
who are going to do the job.
好運，幹掉他們
Good luck, good hunting
但願上帝保佑我們這次行動
and may God speed us on our mission.
來點
Have some?
謝謝，夥計
Thanks, buddy.
從沒聽說過“七趾皮特” 玩成這樣已經很運氣了
You're awfully lucky for guys who never heard of Seven-Toed Pete.
他們告訴我 佛吉尼亞也很適合打獵
They tell me Virginia's a great hunting country, too.
是嗎？對，我們來玩 小夥子們
What's that? Oh, yeah. Let's play, fellows.
- 賭多少？ - 隨便你，門奇
- What's the bet? - It's up to you, Manch.
他們不是說 佛吉尼亞是“總統之鄉”嗎？
Don't they call Virginia the Mother of Presidents?
對，我是說… 賭5個吧
Yeah. I mean... Bet five.
跟10個
Up ten.
- 湯瑪斯.傑佛遜住在那裡吧？ - 是吧
Thomas Jefferson lived there, too, didn't he?
我放棄
I drop.
很多人都住那裡
A lot of guys lived there.
你們確信沒玩過“七趾皮特”嗎？
Are you sure you never played Seven-Toed Pete before?
10個，你的門奇
Makes it ten to you, Manch.
你們那兒的十二指腸病 得到控制了嗎？
Have they finally gotten that hookworm situation under control down there?
佛吉尼亞從來沒有十二指腸病
There never has been a case of hookworm in Virginia.
- 我是一個對對福 - 我是清一色
- I've got a small straight. - Mine's seven to the jack.
我是清對
All pink.
我又輸了，我想睡覺了
Well, that beats. I think I'll turn in.
- 有人贏了很多錢 - 一點點
- Somebody's won a lot of dough. - A little.
- 你的牌不好，門奇 - 是啊
- You just had a run of bad cards, Manch. - Yeah.
我們以後再來玩
What say we get together again pretty soon?
當然，回頭見
Oh, sure. See you later.
門奇，你在佛吉尼亞 沒有什麼書吧？
Say, you haven't got any books on Virginia, have you, Manch?
你們空軍都是一群鴿子 我真想你在海軍
You Army guys are real pigeons. I wish you were in the Navy.
你去睡我的地方，勞森 我想睡你這兒，如果你不介意
You take the bunk, Lawson. I'll sleep here, if you don't mind.
- 為什麼？ - 那裡有如羽毛般舒適柔軟？
- What's the idea? - That thing's as soft as a feather bed.
但我可睡不安穩
I never could sleep in it.
- 不賴啊 - 謝謝
Yeah. It's not bad. Thanks. Thanks a lot.
蘭德爾上尉會告訴我們—些 關於航母起飛的事項
Lieutenant Randall is going to tell us something about a carrier takeoff.
蘭德爾先生
Mr. Randall.
從你們上飛機開始，我開始負責
From the minute you're in your planes, I'm the man to watch.
當你前一個人準備滑行時 請儘快關掉引擎
Have your engines turning over as soon as the man in front of you starts taxiing.
當我要你們加快轉速時 我會給你們這個
When I want you to rev up, I'll give you this.
如果你們的引擎運作得 對我來說不好的話
Now, if your engines don't sound right to me,
我會要你們加大引擎轉速 時間比你們認為的要長一些
I may have to keep you revved up longer than you think necessary,
我會來聽你們的引擎 然後告訴你什麼時候是最佳時機
I can hear your engines and tell when they're missing better than you can.
當我要你開始滑行時 我會給你這個
When I want you to start taxiing, I'll give you this.
然後你們就位 我會給你們最後一次
Now you're in position. I give you a final rev.
然後我丟掉它，你們就起飛
And when I drop it, you're off.
我們會讓你們直飛日本 還有一件事
We'll aim you straight for Japan. One more thing.
旦一我們列隊起飛
Once we're lined up for the takeoffs,
就不會有延誤
there can be no delays.
如果你們的飛機停了 沒有立即起飛
If your plane stalls, if it doesn't start immediately,
如果你們有任何種類的任何麻煩
if you have any trouble of any kind,
我們沒有時間去處理
we won't have time to do anything about it.
海軍會按照命令催促你們離艦
The Navy crew has orders to push the ship overboard
給下一艘飛機讓路
and make way for the next one.
尤里卡中尉有城市和
Lieutenant Jurika has detailed maps and pictures
具體目標的詳盡地圖和照片
of cities and specified targets.
尤里卡先生在日本生活了 很長的時間
Mr. Jurika spent a great many years in Japan.
我想他可以給我們很多東西
I think it might be a good idea if he gave you some idea
關於我們要對付的那些人
of what kind of people you're going to run up against
以防你們被擊落
in case you're forced down.
尤里卡先生
Mr. Jurika.
我是駐日海軍助理隨員
I was Assistant Naval Attach? at our embassy in Japan,
有很長一段時間瞭解 東方各國的經歷
long enough to learn a few things about the Orient.
我們應該怎麼做，尤里卡先生？
Just what should we do, Mr. Jurika?
我們應該怎麼和那些人相處？ 一旦我們掉在了日本
How should we conduct ourselves in case we are forced down over Japan?
我的建議是 不要把自己當作掉在了日本
My advice is, see that you're not forced down over Japan.
我為你們設計的路線 是從這裡開始
The run I've got figured out for you starts here.
這些煙囪是鮮紅的磚石做的 你們一定能找到
The smokestacks are bright red brick, and you can't miss them.
日本最大的熔爐之一
One of the largest smelters in Japan.
然後沿著海岸線每十秒投一次彈
Then, following the line of the bay and allowing 10 seconds between bombs
你們必須清除這個和這個
you should take out this and this.
兩座兄弟倆擁有的機械工廠
Both of them are machine shops owned by brothers,
我忘了叫什麼名字 但我記得我不喜歡它們
I forget their names but I remember I didn't like them.
然後在這裡你們開始丟燃燒彈 你們是怎麼列隊的，勞森
Then on out here to drop your incendiary. How does this line up for you, Lawson?
好，你去投擲燃燒彈，克勒文
Well, you're going to drop them, Clever.
我覺得路線不錯 希望你們也這樣認為
The run seems all right for me if it's okay for you.
我們可以這樣實行 很好
- We can take them out. - Fine.
鐘斯，你們有針對這種路線的訓練嗎？
Jones, have you got the course laid out for this run?
好，到這邊來，小夥子
Yes. Over here, fellows.
你們從這裡起飛 往東京的正西方行駛
Now you'll take off about here. You go due west to Tokyo
以最小巡行航速，大約50英尺高度
at minimum cruising speed, flying at about 50 feet.
到達海岸線，上升到1500英尺
When you hit the bay, get up to about 1,500
完成轟炸路線後下降，離開陸地
complete your bombing run, then down again and out to sea,
- 屋久島南偏東南方向 - 我們能帶上地圖嗎？
- south by southeast to Yakushima. - Can we take the maps with us?
需要的都可以拿上
All you need.
上面沒有什麼標注
Be sure there are no marks on them though,
因為如果你們被捕
which might show the Japs where you came from
可能會洩露你們從哪兒來
in case you're captured.
另外我給第一架飛機 加了4個燃燒彈
By the way, I'm taking off first with four incendiaries.
這樣東京就能為你們美麗燃燒
That should light up Tokyo pretty well for you.
我們到了中國 降落場會不會被日本佔領了？
Suppose by the time we get to China, the Japs have taken over the landing field?
一旦被日本佔領了
The Chinese will arrange a signal for you when you get to the field
你們到達機場時 中國方面會給你們安排信號
if the Japs have captured it.
如果你們一直飛行，最後燃料用盡
If that's the case you've got to keep right on going until you've run out of gas
跳傘離機，然後把飛機毀掉
then bail out and destroy your planes.
是的
Yes.
部署上有些變化
There's just been a change in the disposition
東京上空的阻塞氣球
of the barrage balloons over Tokyo.
這個氣球和這個
This balloon and this one
今早被移到這裡和這裡
were moved this morning to here and here.
這些氣球的變化把我弄暈了
You know, the changes in those balloons threw me.
就象一個整天在浴缸裡 汗流浹背的人一樣
Just think, a bunch of guys sweating all day in a sub
沿著東京灣走來走去
down under Tokyo bay, guys just like us
晚上偷偷摸摸打聽氣球的位置
sneaking up at night to radio balloon positions.
讓我聽到了很多人都在談論 海軍的聲音
Just let me hear anybody talk about the Navy again.
他們很不錯
Boy, they're good.
非常不錯，撲克也打得不錯
Plenty. They're not bad at poker either.
你又在說笑
Oh, you're not kidding.
我盼望在重慶給艾倫什麼禮物
I kind of figured on getting Ellen a present in Chungking, you know,
和服或者什麼
a kimono or something.
但這些海軍把我的錢贏光了
But these Navy guys have cleaned me.
信不信由你，我只剩14美元了
Believe it or not, I've only got 14 bucks.
我也只有8或者10美元能給你了
Well, I got $8 or $10 I could let you have.
不不，我也是想想而已
Oh, no. No. I've been thinking,
這裡一包香煙賣60美分
cigarettes sell for 60 cents a carton on the boat here.
但在重慶 我聽說有人願意出7美元
But in Chungking, I hear the boys will pay seven bucks.
是嗎？
Yeah?
所以我準備在“鴨子”上 裝滿棺材釘
So I figure I may load the duck with coffin nails.
這個主意不錯
Hey, that's an idea.
- 今晚真不錯 - 是啊
- It's a good night for subs. - Yeah.
這真有意恩
You know, it's funny.
小時候，我總是夢想去船上看看
When I was a kid I used to dream about going someplace on a ship.
現在我來了
Well, here I am.
正開往日本
And out there is Japan.
我母親曾經有一個日本園丁
My mother had a Jap gardener once.
他看起來很不錯
He seemed like a nice little guy.
你知道，我並不恨日本人
You know, I don't hate Japs, yet.
是有點意思，我不喜歡他們 但也不恨
It's a funny thing. I don't like them, but I don't hate them.
我想我也是，這種感覺很複雜
I guess I don't either. You get kind of mixed up.
是的
Yeah.
這很難琢磨，但畢竟我們來了
It's hard to figure. Yet here we are.
我最想成為一個航空工程師
All I ever wanted to be was an aeronautical engineer.
我40歲參軍 因為我覺得這是最好的學習機會
I joined the Army in '40 because I figured it was the best way to learn.
我不仇恨任何人
I wasn't sore at anybody.
但突然你就要意識到 你要把一噸多的烈性炸藥
But here you suddenly realize you're going to drop
投放到世界上最大的城市之一
a ton of high explosives on one of the biggest cities in the world.
你有點敏感吧？
You're not getting squeamish, are you?
不不，當然不是
Oh, no, of course not.
我並不掩飾我對 殺害眾多平民的厭惡
I don't pretend to like the idea of killing a bunch of people
但如果我不把炸彈 丟在他們頭上
but it's the case of drop a bomb on them
不久他們就會丟在艾倫頭上
or pretty soon they'll be dropping one on Ellen.
對啊
Yeah, that's right.
我在想到底有多少人 能最後挺過來
I wonder how many of us will pull through.
哦，他們估計一半
Oh, they figure about half.
- 每個人都認為自己是一半當中的一個 - 對
- And everybody thinks he'll be in that half. - Yeah.
你什麼時候結婚，鮑勃？ 當我找到艾倫那樣好的姑娘的時候
- When are you going to get married, Bob? - Oh, when I find somebody like Ellen.
這真好，你知道，就是我們四個
It'd be swell, you know. The four of us.
一切都結束後，我會買一個小農場
You know, when this is over I'd like to get me a small ranch.
養四、五十頭牛什麼的
Something that'd run about 40 or 50 head of cattle.
一口好井，一間好房 這是給孩子們的
A nice well and a house. It'd be wonderful for kids.
我對農場真的很感興趣
I've always been kind of nuts about ranches myself.
在好年景，你可以自己豐衣足食
You know, in a decent year you can make real dough
可以吃得飽飽的 而且還有40頭牛啊
out of 40 head of cattle, if you've got feed.
- 我們為什麼不去幹幹那些 - 你去的話那我也去
- Why don't we do something like that? - Well, I'm game if you are.
- 好的，就這麼說定了 - 好
- Okay, it's a deal. - Good.
當然，如果我們有80頭牛的話 我們就可以大幹一場
Of course, now if we had 80 head of cattle we'd really have ourselves a layout.
是啊，我們自己的肉 牛奶、黃油、雞蛋
- Yeah, and our own meat too. - Oh, yeah, milk, butter, eggs,
所有的一切
the whole works.
一個有自己一隅的人
You know, a guy who's got himself a place,
是不會憂慮什麼的
he doesn't have to worry about anything.
在附近打獵 當然，那很容易
- And with a little hunting near. - Oh, sure, that's easy.
天哪，戰爭結束，我高興得快瘋了
Gosh, I'll be glad when this war ends.
緊急情況時，就不會有集合
In the event of an emergency there will be no assembly.
沒有最後指示，我們立即就起飛
No last minute instructions. We'll just take off.
離開“大黃蜂號”半小時內 出現發動機故障
If you should develop motor trouble within a half hour after leaving the Hornet,
請飛回船艦，並在水面降落
fly back to the ship and land in the water.
海軍會把你們撈出來
The Navy will try to fish you out.
如果是半小時後發生了什麼問題 你就得帶著繼續前進
If trouble should develop after that time, you'll have to keep right on going.
因為那時候 戰艦就要向敵方開火了
Because by that time the fleet will have to fire on any craft overhead.
我不希望你們用完 備用油氣罐後扔掉
I don't want you to throw out the extra cans of gas as you use them.
那樣會給日本日留下追蹤 “大黃蜂號”的線索
That would leave a perfect trail for the Japs to follow back to the Hornet.
把罐子積攢起來，一次全部扔掉
Save the cans and throw them all out at one time.
現在，我再重申一下我前面說的
Now let me repeat something I've said previously.
你們負責轟炸指定的軍事目標 除此之外別無它物
You are to bomb the military targets assigned to you and nothing else.
當然，在這樣的任務過程中 不可能不傷及平民
Of course, in an operation of this kind you cannot avoid killing civilians.
因為戰爭機器是被公民操縱的
Because war plants are manned by civilians.
如果你們有對這種必要的傷亡 有任何道德情感
If any of you have any moral feelings about this necessary killing,
如果你把自己當作一個謀殺者的話
if you feel that you might think of yourself afterward as a murderer,
我希望你能離開，我們會找人代替你
I want you to drop out. We'll find someone to take your place.
我保證沒有人能指責 你的這種情感
And I promise you that no one will blame you for your feelings.
除非計畫有變，否則我們明晚起飛
Barring any sudden switch in plans, we'll take off tomorrow night.
還有一件事
There's one thing more.
當我們在重慶相聚時 我們會安排一場派對
When we meet in Chungking I'm going to throw you a party
這樣你們也可以 和你們的孫子們提起…
that you can tell your grandchildren about.
你們是好樣的 和你們在一起我感到驕檄
You're a great bunch of guys. I'm proud to be associated with you.
祝你們好運
Good luck.
- 12包香煙 - 12包
- 12 cartons of cigarettes. - 12 cartons?
空軍都發了什麼了？
Say, what gives with the Army?
我從未賣過這麼多的香煙
I've never sold so many cigarettes in my life.
我們是煙鬼，你是在吃煙 要什麼樣的？
- We're chain smokers. - You must eat them. What kind will it be?
隨便
Oh, any kind.
- 你只是想要很多煙 - 你猜對了
- You just want lots of cigarettes. - You hit it right on the head.
好吧
All right.
共7.20美元
That'll be $7.20.
我們的航母特遣部隊 已經被敵方水面艦隊發現
Now hear this. Our carrier task force has been sighted by enemy surface vessels.
所有空軍飛行員 準備好你們的飛機
All Army pilots and crews, man your planes for immediate takeoff.
不到3分鐘 我們就能看見日本人了
There goes a Jap just three minutes after we sighted her.
它有2分鐘的時間告訴東京 它看見了什麼
Yeah. That means she had two minutes to tell Tokyo what she saw.
聽著，趕緊裝上炸彈
Now hear this. Get all bombs loaded on the double.
- 你們都準備好了嗎？ - 準備好5天了，長官
- Are you all packed? - Have been for five days, sir.
好的 看看其他人怎麼對付“鴨子”的吧
Good. Better watch how those guys handle the Duck.
是的，長官
I will, sir.
不要告訴其他人小炮塔的事
And don't tell anybody about that bumped turret.
我不會的，長官
I won't, sir.
我們要走了  耶
- Hey, we're off, aren't we? - Yeah!
哦，快炸爛他
Oh, bomb me, daddy!
我想所有的東西都準備好了
I think I've got everything packed.
太好了，謝謝 很抱歉，沒我們沒有
- Swell, thanks. - I'm sorry we couldn't have
準備一個好的天氣給你們
picked out a little better weather for you.
我們會成功的，再會，費爾頓 狠狠揍他們一拳讓他們記住
- We'll make it. So long, Felton. - Give them a pasting they'll never forget.
我們會的，謝謝你們做的一切
We will. Look, thanks for everything.
你們海軍，你很好，再會了
You guys in the Navy, well, you're okay. Be seeing you.
聽這，到飛行甲板檢查 開啟引擎
Now hear this. Clear the flight deck to start engines.
嘿，找我的錢呢？
Hey, how about my change?
他們給了我們15罐備用油 而不是10罐
They're giving us fifteen extra cans instead of ten.
很好，至少現在起飛能讓我們 在白天到達東京
Good. At least getting off now will put us over Tokyo in daylight.
白天不用擔心阻塞氣球
Don't forget about the barrage balloons in daylight too.
下次你就會告訴我不用擔心了
Oh, next you'll be telling me it's good
因為白天你就可以照到照片了
because you can get better pictures in the daytime.
- 你沒開玩笑吧？ - 讓我們再檢查一下
- You're not kidding about that, either. - Let's give her a final check.
嘿，鮑勃
Hey, Bob.
- 什麼？ - 你在前面嗎？
- What? - Are you up ahead?
四號場地
Fourth spot.
重慶見
See you in Chungking.
你說的，兄弟
You said it, brother.
- 他們怎麼樣，杜利德？ - 隨時都可以起飛
- How they doing? - Doolittle will be off any second.
然後是胡佛、霍爾斯通、格雷 然後大衛.鐘斯，我們第七個
Then Hoover, Holstrom, Gray and Davey Jones, we're seventh.
7是幸運的數字
Seven's a lucky number.
嘿，特德 把這個帶上好嗎？
Ted, Ted. Hey, Ted, Ted, hey. Put these some place, will you?
- 這是什麼？ - 燃燒盤
- What are they? - Sizzle platters.
我已經裝了一個留聲機了 但我們沒有地方放唱片
I've got the phonograph in my ship. But I haven't got room for the records.
我們重慶見，跳中國的搖擺舞
We'll meet in Chungking and cut a Chinese rug.
好的，肖特
Okay, Shorty.
- 收好它們，麥克盧爾 - 好的
- Take care of these, will you, McClure? - Right.
飛行員呼叫投彈員 收到，前進，長官
- Pilot to gunner. - Gunner to pilot. Go ahead, sir.
如果有機會注意看一眼小炮塔
Take a look at the turret if you get a chance.
我一直在看，長官 但還是很亂
I've been working on that, sir. She's still jammed.
如果需要就用輔助燃料
We'll use the auxiliary power if we have to.
好的，長官
Right, sir.
我們把自己弄得一團糟 是吧，勞森？
We've got ourselves in a fine jam, haven't we, Lawson?
現在說這些時機真好啊
Well, this is a great time to think of that.
不是，我是說提前起飛
Oh, no, I mean having to take off ahead of schedule.
對不起，達文波特 我想我有點緊張了吧
Oh, I'm sorry, Davenport. I guess maybe I'm a little on edge.
- 炸彈艙檢查完了嗎？ - 檢查完畢
- Bomb bay clear? - Bomb bays clear.
- 左邊檢查完了嗎？ - 檢查完畢
- Clear on right? - Clear on right.
- 右邊檢查完了嗎？ - 檢查完畢
- Clear on left? - Clear on left.
他成功了，他成功了
He made it. He made it.
側翼豎立
Get your flaps up.
嘿
Hey!
祝你們好運，小夥子們 剩下的都交給海軍了
Good luck, fellows. Hand them a couple for the Navy.
- 我們會的，米勒 - 也感謝你
- We sure will, Miller. - And thanks to you.
願和你在一起 再見
Wish I were going with you. So long.
- 再見 - 再見
- So long. - So long.
再見，小夥子們
Goodbye, boys.
我們前面還有四個 開啟引擎
- Four more ahead of us. - Let's start the engines.
走吧
Let's go.
右邊檢查完了嗎？ 右邊檢查完了嗎？
- Clear on right? - Clear on right?
檢查完畢
Clear on right.
左邊檢查完了嗎？
Clear on left?
檢查完畢
Clear on left.
這些海軍在催我們走
Those Navy guys are moving up to push us over.
他們不可能把我們扔出去
They're not gonna toss this ship overboard.
來呀寶貝，使把勁
Come on, baby. Give.
使把勁，使把勁
Give. Give.
檢查水壓
Check hydraulic pressure.
- 水壓正常 - 檢查?車壓力
- Hydraulic pressure okay. - Check brake pressure.
正常
Okay.
鮑勃走了
There goes Bob.
我們前面還有兩個
Two more ahead of us.
檢查燃料加壓器
Check fuel booster.
嘿，空軍，特德
Hey, Army. Ted!
給我也帶些
Give them for me.
我們到重慶時，會告訴他們 海軍也幹得不錯
When we get to Chungking, we'll tell them it was a Navy show too.
他們會發現你們一文不值 加油幹
They'll know that when they see how broke you are. Good hunting.
- 炸彈艙門關閉 - 炸彈艙關閉
- Bomb bay doors closed. - Bomb bays closed.
- 飛行員呼叫，準備就緒了，柴契爾 - 一切就緒，長官
- Pilot to gunner. All set, Thatcher? - Everything okay, sir.
- 機翼下垂 - 機翼下垂
- Wing flaps down. - Wing flaps coming down.
霍爾馬科走了
There goes Hallmark.
我們要走了，夥計們 和你們一起真好
We're taking off, fellows. Happy landings.
嘿
Phew!
耶
Yeah.
雙側機翼豎立
Both the flaps up.
我們沒有把它們放下
We didn't even have them down.
- 你覺得怎麼樣？ - 我想想還忘了什麼
How do you like that? I wonder what else we forgot.
咖啡、三明治、水，夠了
Coffee, sandwiches, water, plenty.
飛行員呼叫柴契爾
Pilot to gunner. Thatcher.
請講，長官
Gunner to pilot. Go ahead, sir.
- 你還好吧，柴契爾？ - 還好，長官
- You all right, Thatcher? - Yes, sir.
你最好開始弄那些罐子了
You'd better get started on those cans.
- 我們已經用掉了40加侖了 - 好的，長官
- We've burned over 40 gallons already. - Yes, sir.
好的，我們上路了
Well, we're on our way.
如果有人走狗屎運了，一定不要放過
If anybody's carrying a rabbit's foot, hang on to it tight.
我們的位置，麥克盧爾
What's our position, McClure?
我估計離海岸還有1小時58分鐘
I figure about an hour and 58 minutes from the coast.
聽見了嗎，柴契爾？ 我們可以隨時靜候那些敵人
Get that, Thatcher? We can expect their fighters any time now.
睜大眼睛 時刻注意，長官
- Keep your eyes open. - Watching, sir.
什麼都看不見 需要試一試這個炮塔嗎？
There's nothing in sight. Could we try out this turret again?
好，打開繼電器開關
Okay. Relay switch on.
運轉正常，先生
It works all right, sir,
但如果我們遇到麻煩 備用動力不能維持多久
but that emergency power's not going to hold out long if we run into trouble.
那就關掉它
Turning it off now.
- 我們離第一批人有多遠？ - 大概一小時
- How far are we behind our first gang? - About an hour.
那我們真的應該想想 怎麼應對麻煩
Then we really can get set for trouble.
是的，但是不像後面那些人 遇到的那樣
Yeah, but nothing like what the guys behind us are going to run into.
晚上作業我感覺要好一些
I'd feel a lot better on a night job.
你聽見左側發動機熄火了嗎？
Did you hear that left engine miss?
沒有，像是有人在嬉笑
No, singing like a lark.
我得聽聽聲音
I must be hearing things.
導航員呼叫
Navigator to pilot.
請講
Pilot to Navigator. Go ahead.
我們應該不久就到達日本海岸
We ought to hit the Japanese coast any minute.
看
Look.
- 看見那個旗子了嗎？ - 看見了
- See that flag? - Yeah.
今天節省炸彈 他們在向我們揮舞示意
- Saving bombs today. - They're waving at us.
他們肯定瘋了
Those guys must be nuts.
直飛日本海岸
Japanese coast straight ahead.
富士山
Fujiyama.
我們現在可以丟點鉛彈
We'll be catching buckshot any second now.
零
Zeros.
- 飛行員呼叫… - 我看見了，長官
- Pilot to... - I saw them, sir.
- 要我打開炮塔的電源嗎？ - 不，等一下
- Shall I turn the power on for the turret? - No, wait a minute.
我不知道他們怎麼了 我想他們沒有看見我們
I don't know what happened to them, sir. I guess they didn't see us.
既然都來了，就好好看一下
There she is fellows. Take a good gander.
當我們凱旋的時候
When we get back home, the folks will want to know what
人們肯定會問我們東京怎麼樣
Tokyo used to look like.
那肯定是大衛.鐘斯的工作了
That must be Davey Jones giving them the works.
飛行員呼叫投彈手 投彈艙開啟
Pilot to bombardier, bomb bay doors open.
我們到了，大紅煙囪 飛行員呼叫投彈手
- There we are, the big red smokestack. - Pilot to bombardier,
- 接近熔爐 - 準備好了
- approaching smelter. - I'm on it.
他們也來了
They've got our altitude.
一個
One away.
兩個
Two away.
三個
Three away.
四個
Four away.
三架戰機出現在左上方 看見了嗎，柴契爾？
- Six fighters just above and to the right. - Have you got them, Thatcher?
準備好了，長官
Ready for them, sir.
他們為何不俯衝？
Why don't they dive?
他們離開了
They're going away.
我們不等他們回來了 我們自己離開這兒
We're not going to wait for them to come back. We're getting out of here.
我想我們非常幸運
Well, I guess maybe we're in that lucky half.
說不定呢，我們還沒到中國
Not yet. Not till we get to China.
真頭痛
Wow. What a headache.
- 你害怕嗎？ - 我還是害怕
- Were you scared? - I'm still scared.
- 麥克盧爾，一切按計劃進行嗎？ - 是的
- McClure, on our course? - On our course.
160加侖，我希望這能堅持到衢州
A hundred and sixty gallons. I hope it's enough to get us to Changchow.
而且也不要日本人先去了那裡
Yeah, and I hope the Japs don't get there first.
消息怎麼樣，麥克盧爾？
What's the dope, McClure?
離衢州200英里
About 200 miles to Changchow.
馬上就要到達海岸了 黑暗裡我們就找不到了
- And we ought to hit the coast any minute. - We'll never find it in the dark.
飛行員呼叫全體機員
Pilot to crew.
我們正在按指示飛行 一旦燃料用完，我們就跳傘
We're going up and flying on instruments. When the gas is gone we'll bail out.
我們快用光了，也許可以著陸 注意一下暗礁和原木
We'll buzz it. Maybe we can land. Keep a lookout for rocks or logs.
著陸準備就緒 麥克盧爾，把槍帶上
All set for landing. McClure, get our guns out.
脫掉降落傘，把救生衣帶上 帶上槍
Take off chutes and be sure your life jackets are on. Carry your guns.
輪子放下，機翼放下
Wheels down. Flaps down.
風速135
Air speed 135.
風速130
130.
110.
我的飛機沒了
I lost my ship.
- 你傷得重嗎？ - 我不…我不知道
- You hurt bad? - I don't... I don't know.
我的手不能動了
I can't move my arms.
你的腳，都快斷了，長官
Your leg, it's all busted up, sir.
找到達文波特了
Get Davenport.
特德，特德，看著我
Ted, Ted, look at me.
孩子和我
That baby and I...
不需要任何東西，除了你…
We won't ever need anything but you.
我們誰都不准害怕，特德
We mustn't either of us be scared about it, Ted,
因為我們的孩子 是我堅信你會回來的理由
because the baby, the baby's why I know you're coming back to us.
勞森
Lawson!
我能開槍嗎，上尉？
Shall I shoot them, Lieutenant?
不，把槍拿著
No, hold it.
- 但他們可能是日本人，長官 - 別開槍，柴契爾
- But they may be Japs, sir. - Don't shoot, Thatcher.
喂
Hey! Hey!
他說他是中國人 他說的英語是什麼？
He says he's Chinese. What's that word for American?
這只腳需要縫合，長官
That leg's got to be sewn up, sir.
它已經爆裂了
It's split wide open.
我，查理
Me, Charlie.
美國人
Americans.
我們是美國人 美國人
- We're Americans. - American.
美國人
Americans.
我們需要醫生，我們需要幫助
We need a doctor, and some help
到衢州
to get to Changchow.
陳開聖
Chiang Kai-shek.
- 我們是朋友，在重慶 - 重慶
- We're his friends. In Chungking. - Chungking!
- 是的 - 就是
- Yes. - That's right.
我們去重慶
We go Chungking.
重慶很多很多天
Chungking many, many days. Many.
醫生，醫生
Doctor. Doctor.
查理，去叫醫生，醫生，查理 請一個醫生來
Charlie, go, go doctor. Charlie, bring doctor here.
查理，請一個醫生來 不然我們會死的
Charlie, bring doctor or we die.
醫生，有一裡遠
Doctor, one li.
裡是中國的距離單位
One li, that's a Chinese mile.
一裡，去
One li. Go.
請醫生來
Bring doctor.
醫生，日本人，日本醫生
Doctor, Japanese man. Japanese doctor.
也許是日本人，日本兵
Maybe Japanese man, Japanese soldier,
過來
come here.
日本人晚上不來
Japanese man no come at night.
船，你們坐船去
Boat, you go boat.
走吧
Let's go.
嘿，幹什麼？
Hey, cut that out.
我想他想和你交換子彈，柴契爾
I think he wants to trade bullets with you, Thatcher.
朋友
Friend.
查理，朋友
Charlie, friend.
查理，走，查理，朋友
Charlie, go. Charlie, friend.
當然，查理，朋友，再見，查理
Sure, Charlie, friend. Goodbye, Charlie.
日本人肯定就在我們周圍
The Japs must be all around us.
- 我想知道其他人去哪裡了？ - 散落在中國的海岸線上了
- I wonder where the rest of the gang is? - Scattered all over the China coast,
如果他們還活著的話
if they're alive.
我以為我快死了
I think I'm going to pass out.
我，特德 娶艾倫為我的合法妻子
- I, Ted, take you, Ellen. - To be my lawfully wedded wife.
為我的合法妻子
To be my lawfully wedded wife.
擁有並且珍惜 擁有並且珍惜…
- To have and to cherish. - To have and to cherish.
直至死亡分離
Until death us do part.
不要切斷我的腳，求你了 不要切斷我的腳
Don't let them cut my leg off. Please, don't let them cut my leg off.
- 不要讓他們切斷你的腳 - 勞森，停下來
- Don't let them cut my leg off. - Lawson, stop it. Lawson.
- 不要 - 勞森
- Don't. - Lawson.
- 怎麼了？ - 你在大叫
- What's the matter? - You were yelling.
謝謝
Thank you.
我叫傅苓
My name is Foo Ling.
我們的東西你們都可以用
Everything we have is yours.
我們知道你們做的一切 我們很敬重你們
We know what you have done and we honor you for it.
我們的導航員兩隻胳膊斷了
Our navigator has both his shoulders broken.
有人可以給他安好嗎？
Is there anybody who can set them for him?
沒有人
No one.
但我們希望幫助能儘快抵達
But we hope that help will soon arrive for you.
謝謝
Thanks.
他們怎麼樣？
How are they?
我們給他們清洗了一下 正在綁傷口
We have washed them. They are bandaged.
但是我們沒有藥
But we have no medicines.
連阿司匹林都沒有
Not even aspirin.
怎麼了？
What's that?
- 這是陳醫生 - 你好
- This is Dr. Chung. - How do you do?
我們走了很久，正準備返程
We've come a long way and we're going home now
我們一直在到處尋找醫生
and we've been hunting a doctor everywhere.
我明白
I understand.
你有什麼其它辦法能解救他們嗎？ 他們都要痛死了
Have you got anything that'll knock them out, Doctor? They're in awful pain.
我去一趟我爸爸的醫院 也許就能得到一些藥品了
We hope to have some medical supplies by the time we reach my father's hospital.
醫院，在哪裡？
Hospital? Where's that?
在臨海，離這裡有60裡遠
In Lin Hai. About 60 li from here.
我來吧，你們接過去 這太好笑了
- I have come to take you there. - It's a funny thing, Doctor.
還有很多的飛機，我們得儘早啟程
There were a lot of planes and we had to take off early.
- 你看見了吧？ - 當然
- You see how it was. - Of course.
他們這狀況是不能走遠路的 醫生
They aren't in any shape to make much of a trip, Doctor.
但我們得馬上轉移他們
We'll have to move them at once.
日本人昨天抓住了你們的一個人 離這兒不遠
The Japanese captured one of your crews yesterday, not very far from here.
很多飛機，我們不知道其他人 情況怎麼樣了
So many planes, and we don't know what happened to the others.
全都在中國海岸帶上了
All up and down the Chinese Coast.
我們的國人正在尋找你們的人
My countrymen are seeking your countrymen.
我們會把他們救活的
We'll bring them through.
我有一些錢，我想把它給你
I have some money. I want to give it to you.
求求你，上尉 你已經給了我們很多了
Please, Lieutenant, you have given us enough already.
什麼？你們在日本投下了炸彈
- What? - The bombs you dropped on Japan.
請休息一下吧
Please, now try to rest.
日本人現在在我們 剛才離開的那個村子
The Japanese, they are in the village we just left.
- 陳 - 派克先生
- Chan. - Mr. Parker.
- 派克太太 - 陳醫生
- Mrs. Parker. - Doctor Chan.
- 他們怎樣？ - 他們狀況很不好
- How are they? - They are very, very sick.
我需要你的?明，日本人有多近？
- I'll need your help. - How close are the Japanese?
我們離開三個小時後 他們佔領了三明
They took Ching Ming three hours after our departure.
有一個美國人已經 落入了他們手中
One of the American crews has already fallen into their hands.
為什麼不把他們直接送到 更好的何塞醫院？
Hadn't they better be taken straight through to Hop Sai?
他們受不了長途行進
They couldn't stand the trip.
這是我爸爸，陳醫生
This is my father, Dr. Chung.
- 其他人，求求你，救救他們 - 不要擔心，上尉
- The others, please, help them. - Please, don't worry, Lieutenant.
我們會照顧好每個人的
We'll take care of everybody.
你不會把它鋸掉吧，醫生？
You won't have to take it off, will you, Doc?
我們不希望，但誰也說不準
We hope not. One cannot tell.
你們已經走了很久了 休息一會吧
You've had a long journey. Now you must rest.
我們團裡有的就是 一點消毒水和一些繃帶
All we had at our Mission was a little antiseptic fluid and some bandages.
但我們已經叫信使 去請求藥物了
But we've sent out runners for supplies.
有什麼辦法可以讓我 把消息送出去嗎？
Is there any way I could get a message out?
我想讓我母親知道我還好
I'd like my mother to know that I'm okay.
整個地區都被日本人佔領了
The whole region's swarming with Japanese.
你們覺得合眾國知道 發生在我們身上的事嗎？
Well, do you think they've heard back in the States what happened to us?
我們一直在聽短波 他們都知道了空襲
We've been listening in on short wave. They know all about the raid,
但顯然，細節並沒有被披露
but apparently they're keeping the details secret
要等到你們剩下的人得救以後
until the rest of your men have been saved.
你們找到其他人了嗎？
Have they found any of the others?
我得到消息說，有一隊人成功脫險 也快到這裡了
We have word that one crew will be coming through here pretty soon now.
我明白，他們中間有一個醫生
I understand there's a doctor among them.
肯定是史密斯上尉那一幫人 對不起
Oh, that must be Lieutenant Smith's crew. Excuse me.
史密斯上尉那一幫人 被解救了，長官
Lieutenant Smith's crew has been rescued, sir.
史密斯的
Smith's?
他們發現了史密斯和懷特醫生 他們正趕過來
They found Lieutenant Smith and Doc White and they're coming here.
唐.史密斯的人 那個醫生和唐.史密斯一起飛行
Don Smith's crew. The Doc was flying with Don Smith.
他們快到了
They'll be here any minute now.
真有意思，是吧？
It's funny, isn't it?
我的意思是 克勒文走的路線也很顛簸啊
I mean the way Clever's head just keeps rocking back and forth,
很顛簸
back and forth.
一定是有人救了克勒文
Somebody ought to help Clever.
我覺得中國人真好
I think the Chinese are a swell bunch of people
但我不敢說他們的音樂
but I can't say I go for their music.
肖特.門奇聽到一小段這個 肯定會崩潰的
Shorty Manch would go all to pieces if he heard a little of this.
對
Yeah.
勞森怎樣了？
How's Lawson?
他的腳好象很糟糕，長官
Well, his leg looks pretty bad, sir.
陳醫生覺得裡面已經壞死了
Dr. Chung thinks gangrene has set in.
好像是日本零式飛機
Looks like a Jap Zero.
你們應該不管我，繼續走下去
You guys ought to go on and leave me.
我經常覺得我就要死掉了 我聽見他們說什麼了
They think I'm passed out half the time and I hear what they say.
日本人正在不斷逼近 你們為什麼不走？
The Japs are coming closer all the time. Why don't you guys go?
我們不在這兒逗留 是因為你，勞森
We're not sticking around here because of you, Lawson.
- 我們都不能行走了 - 我在想
- None of us here are able to travel yet. - I was just thinking.
我想我和艾倫再也不能滑雪了
I guess Ellen and I aren't going to ski anymore.
那太糟了
That's too bad.
我會給她講一些有意思的東西
I was going to teach her some fancy stuff.
別那樣說，你正在恢復健康
Now don't start talking like that. You're going to pull through all right.
你覺得一個女孩會怎樣？ 我是說艾倫和我都很喜歡滑雪
What do you think a girl would do? I mean, say Ellen and I like to ski.
他們把我的腳鋸掉 真有點搞笑，不是嗎？
Be kind of funny if they cut my leg off, wouldn't it?
你為什麼不試看睡會兒覺
Why don't you try to go to sleep?
是有點搞笑
Yeah, it'd be kind of funny, all right.
你和一個有兩隻胳膊 兩條腿的人結了婚
You marry a guy, he's got two arms and two legs.
然後他回來了，但什麼都沒有了
Then he comes back and he hasn't any.
我是張醫生，那些小夥子呢？
- I am Dr. Chung. - Where are the boys?
你好，老爹
How are you, Pop?
路上還好吧？
Did you have a good trip?
在這兒呢 嘿，夥計們
- Here they are. - Hi, fellas.
怎麼樣了？ 你還好吧？
- How are you? - How you doing?
你好，軍官 見到你們真高興
- Hello, Sarge. - It's good to see you.
天啊，你們到底發生了什麼？ 不是很嚴重
- Holy Joe, what happened to you guys? - Nothing serious.
“鴨子”忘記鳧水了
The Duck forgot to duck.
是啊，麥克盧爾在盡力 做好他的飛行
Yeah, McClure's been trying to do his own flying ever since.
真像大屠殺的倖存者
This really looks like something left over from a massacre.
你們看起來也不好啊
Well, you guys don't look so good yourselves.
聞起來也是
You don't smell so good either.
這不是我們的錯 好好洗一次澡也無濟於事
Well, there's nothing wrong with us that a good bath won't fix.
我也想這麼說 吃得怎麼樣？
- I wish we could say the same for you. - How's the grub around here?
我想吃上等的厚牛排和法國炸洋蔥
I think I'd like a good thick steak, French fried onions
還有烤土豆，多加點黃油
and a baked potato with plenty of butter
再來三瓶酒…
and about three bottles of beer...
你只有吃豆芽之類的東西
You'll take bean sprouts and like them.
- 勞森和達文波特在哪兒？ - 他們在樓上
- Say, where's Lawson and Davenport? - They're upstairs.
勞森的狀況很不好 你最好去看看他
- Lawson's in pretty bad shape. - You better go up and see him.
他很需要你，醫生
He needs you bad, Doc.
再次見到你們，真的感覺很好
Well, it's certainly good to see you fellows again.
嘿，老爹 這裡的炒雜燴菜怎麼樣
Hey, Pop, how's the chop suey around here?
他不會說英語
He doesn't speak English.
對不起，老爹
I'm sorry, Pop.
肖特跳下來時 有兩把45式，一把44式來福槍
Yeah, and when Shorty jumped, he had two.45s, a.44 rifle,
一把22式自動槍，他自己的 魯格爾手槍，一把獵刀，一把寶蔭刀
a.22 automatic, that Luger of his, a hunting knife, a Bowie knife
- 和一柄斧子 - 真走運
- and an ax. - What a guy.
他把自己的襯衣裡塞滿了巧克力棒 但卻忘了系上衣領扣
He stuffed his shirt full of chocolate bars but he forgot to button his collar.
所以當他拉開開降繩時
So when he pulled the rip cord,
他的那些糖果就掉在 中國北方的土地上了
he just naturally molted candy all over North China.
- 他的照片呢？ - 和飛機一起沒了
- What happened to his photograph? - It went down with the ship.
第二天早上 門奇被中國人的少見多怪嚇住了
Next morning Manch scared the Chinese right out of their wits.
他們不知道人類可以長這麼高
They didn't know anything human grew that tall.
鮑勃.格雷呢？
What about Bob Gray?
他很好 我在想他已經動身去重慶了
He's okay. I think they moved on to Chungking.
那個人我，查理 代我問你們好
Oh, yeah, and that guy "Me, Charlie" said to tell you hello.
如果不是查理的話 我們第一天就被日本人抓住了
If it hadn't been for Charlie, the Japs would have had us that first day.
是啊，我們也是
Yeah, us too.
總有一天我要回去 和那個人並肩作戰
I'd like to come back some day and fight alongside that guy.
我們也是
Me, too.
好了，今天就到這兒了
Well, it's all over.
讓我們節省點話題 留到明天
Let's save some of this talk for tomorrow.
一品脫半，還不錯
A pint and a half, that's not bad.
你們該睡覺了
You'd better get to bed now.
你真是個老奶奶，醫生
You're an old grandma, Doc.
但是我會慢點的，作為對你的感激
But I'll take it slow, just as a favor to you.
再會，勞森
Be seeing you, Lawson.
謝謝醫生
Thanks, Doc.
腳怎麼樣，醫生？
How's the leg, Doc?
不算好，勞森
It's not good, Lawson.
接下來的48小時會有個決斷的
The next forty-eight hours will tell the story.
好吧，謝謝你
Well, thank you.
- 嘿，唐 - 哦
- Hey, Don. - Yeah?
我們到了以後 叫杜利德搞一個派對
Tell Doolittle to hold off that party till we get there.
好的，達文波特，我們等你
Okay, Davenport. We'll wait for you.
- 柴契爾呢？ - 他和勞森在一起，他很好
- Where's Thatcher? - He's in with Lawson. He'll be right out.
Okay.
我希望你在康復之前 讓我一直待在這裡
I wish you would let me stay here until you're ready to go, sir.
這些人會很好的照顧我的
These people will take care of us.
你們沒有理由留在附近 而且還有可能被抓到
There's no reason for you fellows to hang around and maybe get caught.
是啊，我知道，但日本人來了 我們遲早都要走
Yeah, I know, but I might come in handy if the Japs show up, sir.
柴契爾，當你回到美國的時候
Thatcher, when you get back to the States,
如果遇見了我的妻子
if you should run into my wife,
就告訴她我很好
just tell her I'm okay.
不要讓她知道有什麼不對勁了
Don't let her know about anything being wrong.
我明白，長官
I understand, sir.
代我向那個比令斯的女孩問個好
And say hello for me to that girl in Billings.
我會的，長官
That I will, sir.
- 再見 - 再見，柴契爾
- Goodbye. - Goodbye, Thatcher.
早上好
Good morning.
- 早上好，勞森 - 你好，醫生
- Good morning, Lawson. - Hi, Doc.
我儘量不傷著你，勞森 我得仔細看看這個
I'll try not to hurt you, Lawson. I'll have a look at this.
謝謝
Thanks.
你要割下這條腿嗎？
You going to take the leg, Doc?
我想是這樣的
Yeah, I think so.
我們討論過了，除此之外別無他法
We talked it over and there's nothing else to do.
把一個人的腿割下 有些不近人情
It's pretty rough to have to cut a man's leg off.
但我覺得沒什麼事
I guess it'll be all right.
畢竟，一隻木腳就像一個高腳背的腳 穿上了一隻鞋
After all, a wooden leg is just kind of like wearing a shoe with a high instep.
什麼時候開始？
When are you gonna do it?
現在我會給你打一針
I might as well give you a shot right now.
你是說你有什麼東西 可以讓我昏過去？
You mean we have something to knock me out?
我們的信使今早帶來了麻醉劑
Our runners arrived with anesthetic this morning.
只是脊柱麻醉，勞森
It'll only be a spinal, Lawson.
腰部以下你不會有任何疼痛感 但還是會有知覺
You won't feel anything from the waist down, but you'll be conscious.
這已經是最好的了
That's the best we can do.
好的
Oh, swell.
我會仔細看著你們 不會讓你們多割下一點
I can watch you and make sure you don't take off too much.
好的，勞森 我們要把你反轉過來了
All right, Lawson. We'll have to roll you over.
可能會花上一些時間
It'll take a little time to work.
我們把你反過來到手術室裡去
We'll get you over to the operating room.
- 醫生 - 是的
- Doc? - Yes?
- 你們會切多高？ - 不會太高
- How high are you going to cut? - Oh, not too high.
- 我會有膝蓋嗎，醫生？ - 恐怕沒有了，勞森
- Will I have a knee, Doc? - I'm afraid not, Lawson.
- 有感覺嗎？ - 沒有，醫生，我…
- Any feeling there? - No. Look, Doc.
當麻醉劑作用消失前 我們不能浪費時間
We can't waste any time, Lawson. When that anesthetic wears off,
- 我們沒時間了 - 好的，只有一件事
- we haven't got any more. - Okay, but just one thing more.
說吧
Yes.
如果發生什麼不測
If anything happens,
不要讓艾倫知道手術的事
don't let Ellen know anything about the operation.
她最好能夠以為 我是完整的死去的
She might just as well think I died while all in one piece.
好的，勞森 現在你沒有感覺了
All right, Lawson. Now, you're not going to feel this.
但你有可能緊張 跳起來或是怎麼的
But you might get nervous and jump or something,
所以護士們要抓緊你
so the nurses are going to hold you.
好的，醫生
Okay, Doc.
開工吧
Fire away.
當你說：“沒有膝蓋”時 你沒開玩笑吧？
Oh, when you said "no knee," you weren't kidding.
如果我切低了，一切都得重來
If I cut any lower we might have to do it again
你的身體肯定受不了
and your system couldn't take it.
麻醉效力怎麼了，醫生？
What're you stalling for, Doc?
我們在盡力，勞森，放鬆一點
We're doing the best we can, Lawson. Take it easy.
好的，只是再快一點
Okay. Only hurry.
好像我能感覺到另一隻腳了
It seems like I'm beginning to feel my other leg.
好像我的腳能動了，醫生
It seems like I can move my toes, Doc.
我想我能轉動我的腳踝了 快點，醫生，我想我能轉動了
I think I can move my ankle. Hurry, Doc, I'm sure I can.
快點，醫生，快點
Hurry, Doc, hurry.
- 喂 - 喂，艾倫
- Hello. - Hello. Hello, Ellen?
- 特德，你在哪兒？ - 我在一個木屋裡
- Ted, where are you? - I'm in a lumber camp.
我必須在一個泥坑裡強行著陸
I had to make a forced landing in a mud puddle.
- 你沒受傷吧？ - 不，一點掛傷都沒有
- You aren't hurt, are you? - No, not a scratch.
- 你把聖誕樹都裝飾好了嗎？ - 是的，特德，你真該來看看
- Have you got the tree all fixed? - Oh, yes, Ted. You should just see it.
太美了，樹下有東西嗎？
- It's so beautiful. - Anything under it?
- 有啊 - 好的，讓我們打開看看
- Oh, yes. - Well, let's open them up.
- 我們不能那樣 - 我們可以，去打開
- Oh, we can't do that. - Sure we can. Go ahead.
那好吧，你這樣說了
Well, if you say so.
我的飛機毀了 這個耶誕節有被騙的感黨
I'm not going to be cheated out of my Christmas by a cracked up airplane.
哦，特德 這是我一生中見過的…
Oh, Ted, it's the most beautiful
最美的一盒糖果
box of candy I've ever seen in my whole life.
周圍還有什麼嗎？
Good. Isn't there maybe something else lying around?
- 讓我瞧瞧，還有 - 好的，打開看看
- Let me see. Yes, there is. - Well, open it.
是一個絲巾，好像是手工制的
It's a silk scarf. And it looks like it's handmade, too.
- 上面有我名字的首字母 - 這不公平
- I'll bet it's got my initials on it. - That's not fair.
我打開時 你偷偷看了一眼
You peeked while I was making it.
我是瞭解我的妻子啊
I just know my wife.
- 特德，我真想你在我的身邊 - 我也是，甜心
- Oh, Ted, I wish you were here. - So do I, honey.
今晚我會想你的
I'll be thinking of you tonight.
我會坐在聖誕樹下 打開收音機，放著聖誕頌歌
I'll sit in front of the tree and turn the radio on to Christmas carols
不停想念你
and just think of you.
謝謝你們，謝謝你們，童子軍
Thank you. And thank you, scouts.
我們所有人都由衷感謝你們…
I mean, all the fellows would like to thank you very much,
為我們付出的所有
for everything.
上尉，我父親叫我把這個給你們
Lieutenant, my father has asked me to present this to you.
它從15世紀開始 就一直留在我們家了
It has been in our family since the fifteenth century.
父親讓我告訴你 美好的東西永遠屬於美麗的人
Father begs me to tell you that beauty belongs to beauty,
讓你把這個東西帶給你的妻子 就算是對她的敬意了
and asks that you honor him by presenting it to your wife.
謝謝，謝謝
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
我沒想到你知道艾倫，我的妻子
I didn't know that you knew about Ellen, my wife.
你說過很多次了
You spoke of her a number of times.
上面寫著： “這是在日本投下炸彈的美國英雄
It says, "This is an American hero who has bombed Japan.
當他們來到中國人中間時
"Whenever he goes among the people of China,
請尊敬他們
"let him be accorded respect and honor."
他剛從高材來
He has just come from Kow Chai.
你們有一個人被捕了
Another one of your crews has been captured
日本人正朝這個方向來
and the Japanese are moving in this direction.
我想過幾天，勞森才能行走
I think Lawson will be able to travel in a couple of days.
沒有什麼，醫生 我現在就可以走了
There's nothing wrong with me, Doc. I can travel right now.
我擔心幾天的時間太長了
I'm afraid a couple of days will be too long.
這是王強
This is Wang Tsung.
他從他們的高材村一路趕來
He has walked all the way from his native village of Kow Chai.
他想送給美軍盟友們一件 表達敬意的禮物
And he begs the honor of presenting gifts to his American Allies.
謝謝
Thank you.
Thanks.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝，非常感謝
Thank you. Thank you very much.
他感覺比我還糟
He felt a lot worse than I did.
我已經感覺好多了
There, I can get along pretty well already.
我必須得說 你第一次下床，康復得非常好
I should say very well for your first day out of bed.
我覺得我還要小心一點
I guess, I'll have to be a little more careful.
我可不想讓人看見我這樣
I don't ever want anybody to see me do that.
我想讓人看看，我有了一隻新腳了
I don't want anybody to see me till I get a new leg.
懷特上尉的消息
Lieutenant White, word just came.
美軍飛機將在明天下午5點 從衢州機場接你們離開
The American plane will pick you up in Changchow tomorrow afternoon at 5:00.
太好了
Wonderful.
他說如果我們不快點的話 日本人就要捷足先登了
He says if we don't hurry, the Japanese may get there first.
- 你們什麼時候走？ - 我們想待在這裡
- When are you leaving? - We're going to stay here.
我們已經很習慣了
We're quite used to it, you know.
- 來，這些能派上用場 - 謝謝
- Here. This may come in handy. - Thank you.
你和派克先生為我們做了很多
You and Mr. Parker have done so much for us,
我們不會忘記的
and we'll never forget it.
- 再見，勞森 - 再見
- Goodbye, Lawson. - Goodbye.
- 祝你好運 - 再見
- Good luck. - Thank you, sir.
- 再見，願上帝保佑你 - 再見，謝謝
- Goodbye. God bless you. - Goodbye. Thank you.
我父親想讓我告訴你們 你們的到來讓他覺得很光榮
My father wishes me to tell you that you have honored us with your visit
他會一直為你們的平安回國祈禱的
and that he will offer prayers for your safe return to America.
他不和我們一起走嗎？
Isn't he coming along with us?
父親要和他的老鄉們待在一起
Father feels that he must stay with his people.
這裡的人們需要他
They will need him here.
再見，先生
Goodbye, sir.
- 再見，醫生 - 再見，先生
- Goodbye, Doctor. - Goodbye, sir.
再見，醫生，感謝你們做的一切 但願我們能再次相見
- Goodbye, Doc, and thanks for everything. - I hope, sir, that we may meet again.
一定會的，醫生
That goes double, Doc.
再見，醫生，謝謝你
Goodbye, Doctor, and thank you.
謝謝你
Thank you.
如果有機會到美國來 來找我好嗎？
If you ever come to the States, Doctor, look me up, will you?
在波特蘭的黃頁裡找得到我
I'll be in the Portland telephone directory.
- 好的 - 再見，醫生
- With pleasure. - Goodbye, Doctor.
我很難過，上尉
I have one sorrow, Lieutenant,
我們沒有足夠的藥品 來減輕你的疼痛
that we did not have the medicine to ease your pain.
- 你救了我的命，醫生 - 我希望有一天你還能回來
- You saved my life, Doc. - I hope someday you will come back to us.
我會回來的，也許不是我們自己
We'll be back, maybe not us ourselves
有可能是像我們這樣的其他人 我很願意成為他們當中的一員
but a lot of guys like us. And I'd like to be with them.
因為你們是我們最親近的人 謝謝，先生，再見
- Because you're our kind of people. - Thank you, sir, and goodbye.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
- 來坐下 - 謝謝
- Go ahead, sit down. - Thank you.
我知道你的感覺，握著試一試
I know how you feel. Take it for a while.
謝謝
Thanks.
感覺到了嗎？
Smell that?
那是美利堅，那是美國
That's America. That's the USA.
每一次我航行歸來時 她都變得更加光彩照人
Every time I make a trip back, she smells better and better.
是啊
Yeah.
我想我知道你的意思 我來自匹茲堡
- I think I know what you mean. - I'm from Pittsburgh.
可能你覺得很怪，但是…
I know it may seem screwy to you, but
我能隱隱約約聞到煤煙的味道
it seems to me as if I can smell some of that coal smoke
馬上就到老孟農加希拉河了 有點不可思議吧？
right off the old Monongahela River. That sound crazy?
不，我來自加州 已經聞道橘子的味道了
No. I'm from California and I can smell orange blossoms.
不可能，那兒太遠了 絕對是來自佛羅里達的
Oh, it couldn't be, that's too far. It must come from Florida.
如果你想吃的話，一定得吃加州的橘子
Oh, if you want flavor, you've got to have a California orange,
但只是聞聞的話，佛羅里達就夠了
but for smelling, Florida's just as good.
喂…是的
Hello. Yes.
什麼？
What's that?
- 等一會兒，艾倫 - 什麼？
- Just a minute. Ellen. - Yes?
艾倫，華盛頓來的電話
Ellen, Washington on the phone.
你好
Hello?
你好，我是勞森夫人
Yes, this is Mrs. Lawson.
你好上校，杜利德上校
Hello, Colonel. I mean General Doolittle.
哦，我很好，謝謝
Oh, yes, I'm fine, thank you.
非常興奮，將軍
No, not a bit excited, General.
他回來了，媽媽 特德回來了，他回來了
Oh, he's back, Mother. Ted's back. He's back.
好的將軍，他怎麼樣了
Oh yes, General, how is he?
哦
Oh, yes.
我能理解
I understand.
我當然
Of course, I do.
是的，我有準備了
Yes, I'll be ready.
我知道，我知道
I know, I know.
你真的很好，將軍
Oh, that's so nice of you, General.
好的，謝謝哦 謝謝你，將軍
Yes, thank you. Oh, yes, thank you, General.
謝謝
Thank you.
哭出來吧，親愛的
Just cry, darling.
哭出來
Cry it out.
他今天早上到的，媽媽
He got in this morning, Mother.
杜利德將軍剛才見到了 他這是真的
General Doolittle just saw him, so it's true.
杜利德將軍給我寄了一張機票
General Doolittle's sending a plane ticket for me.
特德不想見我
Ted doesn't want to see me.
他不想見我，因為他失去了一條腿
He doesn't want to see me because he's lost his leg
他甚至想把我瞞住
and he doesn't even want me to know it's happened
他有了一隻新腿並且能用以後
till he gets a new leg and learns how to use it.
這都不重要
As if it would make any difference.
只要他還活著
As if anything would make any difference to me as long as he's alive.
哦，我得去見他，我得去見他
Oh, I'm going to see him, I'm going to see him.
哦
Well,
我們得趕緊打點行李
that means we have to get your clothes ready in a hurry.
我的衣服從洗衣房裡取回來了嗎？
Have my things come back from the cleaners yet?
我看我得帶上這件衣服
Let's see, I'll take this suit.
和我的藍外套，他最喜歡了
And my blue coat. He always liked it best.
我帶不了這麼多 我帶不了這麼多好看的衣服
I can't take any of these things. I can't take any of my pretty clothes.
我穿起來不合適了
They don't fit me anymore.
你覺得特德會注意嗎？
Do you think Ted's going to pay any attention
會注意到你穿的衣服 和你的樣子嗎？
to what kind of clothes you wear or how you look?
他會的
He always did.
媽媽，我很害怕
Oh, Mother, I'm scared.
沒什麼可怕的
There's nothing to be frightened about.
很多人都失去了腳或手
Lots of people lose a leg or arm
- 但還是繼續過著正常人的生活 - 我不是害怕特德
- and continue living perfectly normal lives. - I'm not scared about Ted.
- 我害怕我自己 - 你自己？
- I'm scared about me. - About you?
你知道，時過境遷 很多丈夫和妻子就分開了
Well, you see, most husbands and wives are together while things are changing.
丈夫總是那樣 因為…因為這總是在發生
Husbands get used to things like that because, well, they're around.
特德走了好長一段時間 這段時間我又瘦了
Ted's been gone all this time and when he went away, I was so slim.
每次他走了，他總會這樣覺得
All the time he's been gone, he's been thinking of me like that.
特德愛你 愛倫，你也愛他
Ted loves you Ellen, and you love him.
這就是你們沒有人會覺察到 對方變化的原因
That's why neither of you is going to notice any change when you meet.
- 你這樣認為嗎，媽媽？ - 是的
- Do you think so, Mother? - I know so.
還有，如果我穿這樣的衣服的話
All the same, if I held my coat like this
我走在屋子裡 你不覺得有一點點…
when I walk into the room, don't you think it would hide me,
把我內心隱藏起來的感覺
just a little?
你好，勞森，感覺如何？
Hello, Lawson. How're you feeling?
- 很好，長官 - 你看起來不錯
- Pretty good, sir. - You look fine.
謝謝長官
Thank you, sir.
- 你不坐下嗎，長官？ - 哦，謝謝
- Won't you sit down, sir? - Yeah, thanks.
- 有什麼打算？ - 關於什麼？
- Well, got any plans? - About what, sir?
關於未來想做點什麼？
Well, about the future. Have you decided what you're going to do?
沒怎麼想，長官
Not particularly, sir.
我一直想成為一個航空學工程師
I always wanted to be an aeronautical engineer.
退伍以後
I suppose I'll start studying again
我想我得重新學習
after they muster me out.
誰說你會退伍？
Who said they'd muster you out?
我對任何人都沒什麼用了 沒有了…
Well, I won't be much use to anybody with a...
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
你認為我們會讓 擁有你這樣經歷的人離開嗎？
Do you think we'd let a man of your experience get away from us?
- 很好，長官，謝謝 - 你不要謝我
- Well, that's fine, sir. Thank you. - Don't thank me.
- 我突然想到了一些事，勞森
I just happened to think of something, Lawson.
- 什麼？
Yes, sir?
你的妻子呢？她知道你回來嗎？
What about your wife? Does she knew you're back?
- 不知道，長官 - 為什麼？
- No, sir. - Why not?
我想等我有一隻新腳 然後傷疤修復以後
Well, I thought I'd wait till I get my new leg and my scars fixed up.
那樣她就不會感到很震驚了
It won't be so much of a shock to her that way.
震驚？ 你娶的是一個怎樣的女孩？
Shock? What kind of a girl did you marry, anyway?
她很好，長官 她是一個出色的女孩
She's okay, sir. She's a fine girl.
那麼她就應該知道…
Well then, she deserves to know.
並且應該看見你
She deserves to see you too.
不不，長官 如果你不介意，我會一直等下去
No, no, sir. If you don't mind, I'd rather wait.
當我再次見到艾倫時 我一定會盛裝打扮
When I see Ellen again, I'm going to be all dressed up
而且有了一隻新腿
and have a new leg.
帶她去鎮上最好的地方
And I'm going to take her out to the best place in town
和她跳舞
and I'm going to dance with her.
- 那還要等上一段時間，勞森 - 不，長官
- That may be quite a while, Lawson. - No, sir.
你瞧我康復得很快，可能一兩個月…
You see, I'm getting along fine. And in a month or two...
兩個月你就得工作了 繁重的工作
In a month or two you'll be back at work, hard work.
好吧，我會時常來看你的，勞森
Well, I'll try to drop in on you again, Lawson.
- 希望你能來，長官 - 再見
- I hope you can, sir. - Goodbye.
再見，長官
Goodbye, sir.
你妻子快生小孩了，是吧？
Your wife's going to have a baby, isn't she?
是的，長官
Yes, sir.
我也有孩子，兩個，都在服役
I've got a couple of kids myself, both in the service.
勞森，如果我的孩子或者其他人的孩子 遇到這種情況
You know, Lawson, if my kids and all the other kids who are in this thing
都能處理自如，當然我不想看到
could fix it so this would really be the last one,
你孩子會好起來的，是吧？
your kid would get quite a break, wouldn't he?
他會的，長官
He sure would, sir.
我不得不來
I just had to come.
特德，特德，讓我來幫你
Ted, Ted, Ted. Let me help you.
別這樣，艾倫，會傷到孩子的
Don't, Ellen. You'll hurt the baby.
當最慘烈的時候
When things were worst,
當希望渺茫的時候
when there didn't seem to be any chance at all,
我能看見你的面龐，你雋秀的面龐
I could see your face, your beautiful face.
我知道你歸來了，特德
I knew you were coming home, Ted.
告訴我，親愛的
Tell me, honey.
為什麼你這麼可人？
How come you're so cute?
我找到了一個如此帥氣的小夥子 我必須得這樣啊
I had to be if I was going to get such a good looking fellow.
劇  終 謝謝觀賞
English